<item>
		<title>101 RR Diversity with Ashe Dryden</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/i9gyUxLv5j8/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/101-rr-diversity-with-ashe-dryden/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ashe Dryden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1280</guid>
		<description>Panel Ashe Dryden (twitter github blog) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:13 &amp;#8211; Diversity Disclaimer 01:39 &amp;#8211; Ashe Dryden Introduction Ruby Freelancers Independent Developer [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/i9gyUxLv5j8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/101-rr-diversity-with-ashe-dryden/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR101Diversity.mp3" length="90608683" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Ashe Dryden (twitter github blog)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog) </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Ashe Dryden (twitter github blog)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:13 - Diversity Disclaimer
01:39 - Ashe Dryden Introduction


	Ruby Freelancers
	Independent Developer and Conference Organizer

01:59 - Why should we take steps to increase diversity?


	Diverse teams work together better
	Cisgender
	There are Ladies Present: Uncle Bob

11:07 - Helping to make the community diverse


	Use your visibility to become a role model
	Address inappropriateness

14:50 - Standing up for others/Stopping inappropriate behavior


	“White Knighting”
	“Hey, that’s not cool.”

21:50 - Apologizing &amp; Making Mistakes


	Recipe for Ice
	Avdi's How to Apologize
	Josh’s Apology Recipe
	“Intent is not magic”
	Brené Brown: Listening to shame

34:19 - Privilege


	Intersectionality
	Anti-Oppression 101 by Lindsey Bieda &amp; Steve Klabnik
	Dykes to Watch Out For by Alison Bechdel
	The Bechdel test
	Majority and being chosen on merit
	Attrition
	The Pipeline Problem

50:39 - Biases


	What if every Olympic sport was photographed like beach volleyball? by Nate Jones
	Implicit Association Test
	Subconscious Biases
	Why Your Brain Sees Men As People And Women As Body Parts - Forbes

59:03 - Allies


	Accessibility
	Disappointing and dangerous experience as a person with disabilities at a conference

01:02:22 - Improving empathy
01:05:44 - Progress and Movement


	Feminism
	Are you a Feminist?
	Social Justice
	Representing your community

01:17:21 - Acknowledging diversity while still having fun
01:20:31 - Raising children to thrive in a diverse community
01:24:30 - Resources


	Anti-Oppression 101 by Lindsey Bieda &amp; Steve Klabnik
	MINASWAN: Bryan Liles
	My Technology Will Be Intersectional or It Will Be BULLSHIT!: Lightning Talk Edition by Julie Pagano
	Ruby Midwest - Must Have 10+ Years People Experience by Ashe Dryden

Picks

	Brené Brown: The power of vulnerability (David)
	Brené Brown: Listening to shame (David)
	The Gifts of Imperfection: Let Go of Who You Think You’re Supposed to Be and Embrace Who You Are by Brené Brown (David)
	Daring Greatly: How the Courage to Be Vulnerable Transforms the Way We Live, Love, Parent, and Lead by Brené Brown (David)
	I Thought It Was Just Me (but it isn’t): Making the Journey from “What Will People Think?” to “I Am Enough” by Brené Brown (David)
	Jay Smooth: How To Tell People They Sound Racist (Josh)
	What If The Male Avengers Posed Like The Female One? (Josh)
	The Women (Josh)
	Velvet Geek - Black Velvet Painting For Your Inner Nerd (Josh)
	St. Augustine, Florida (Avdi)
	The Walking Dead (James)
	Rolls Mic Mute (Chuck)
	Shit Men Say to Men Who Say Shit to Women on the Street (Ashe)
	#RubyThanks (Ashe)

Book Club
The Rails View by John Athayde and Bruce Williams: Read along with us! We will be discussing the book with John and Bruce and the episode will air on Wednesday, May 8th, 2013.

Next Week
Rhetoric with Joseph Wilk
Transcript
DAVID:  So, we’re not going to talk about the thing you said to me at Mountain West?

[Laughter]

DAVID:  It’s going to come forward sooner or later, Charles.

[Laughter]

JOSH:  David, let's just put it behind us and move on.

CHUCK:  I'm being conspicuously quiet.

[Laughter]

DAVID:  I'm not sure I like your tone.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by The Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

CHUCK:  Hey everybody, and welcome to Episode 101 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have David Brady.

DAVID:  Hello from Salt Lake City. Just like Barack Obama,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:34:23</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR101Diversity.mp3" fileSize="90608683" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/101-rr-diversity-with-ashe-dryden/</feedburner:origLink></item>