<item>
		<title>102 RR Rhetoric with Joseph Wilk</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/AHEZRcW9uVI/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/102-rr-rhetoric-with-joseph-wilk/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joseph Wilk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1290</guid>
		<description>Panel Joseph Wilk (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Discussion 00:55 &amp;#8211; Joseph Wilk Introduction 01:43 &amp;#8211; Confreaks &amp;#124; Ruby Conference 2012: Someone is Wrong by Joseph Wilk 02:55 &amp;#8211; Rhetoric Amphora 04:35 &amp;#8211; Why [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/AHEZRcW9uVI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/102-rr-rhetoric-with-joseph-wilk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR102Rhetoric.mp3" length="63384911" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Joseph Wilk (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) - Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Joseph Wilk (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)

Discussion
00:55 - Joseph Wilk Introduction
01:43 - Confreaks | Ruby Conference 2012: Someone is Wrong by Joseph Wilk
02:55 - Rhetoric


	Amphora

04:35 - Why should rhetoric be important to programmers?


	Communication
	Building for the real world

06:33 - Persuasion


	Persuasion vs Winning
	Writing persuasive code
	Growth of human factors in application development: Alistair Cockburn

11:59 - Expressing ideas via programming languages


	Creating Passionate Users: When only the glib win, we all lose
	YouTube | Growing a Language by Guy Steele
	“Autistic Language”

19:59 - Literate Programming
24:35 - Emotions and Words


	Thank You for Arguing: What Aristotle, Lincoln, And Homer Simpson Can Teach Us About the Art of Persuasion by Jay Heinrichs
	Past Tense/Forensic Debate: Seeks to find out why or how something happened; to fix blame
	Present Tense/Ethical Debate: Seeks to divide the listeners into tribes pro/con; for/against
	Future Tense/Deliberative Debate: Seeks to choose among alternatives

35:59 - Rhetoric of Tools


	Six Thinking Hats
	Dreyfus model of skill acquisition
	Persuasion by authority

46:36 - Rhetoric and persuasion in code

Picks

	Thank You for Arguing: What Aristotle, Lincoln, And Homer Simpson Can Teach Us About the Art of Persuasion by Jay Heinrichs (David)
	Crucial Conversations: Tools for Talking When Stakes Are High by Kerry Patterson (David)
	Crucial Confrontations: Tools for Resolving Broken Promises, Violated Expectations, and Bad Behavior by Kerry Patterson (David)
	The Bromeliad Trilogy: Truckers, Diggers, and Wings by Terry Pratchett (David)
	HandBrake (Avdi)
	Terry Pratchett Movies: Going Postal, The Color of Magic, Hogfather (Avdi)
	The Gentle Art of Verbal Self Defense by Suzette Haden Elgin (Katrina)
	Procrastination Is Not Laziness | Thought Catalog (Katrina)
	Dynamic Method Definitions | Tenderlovemaking (James)
	MRI's Method Caches | James Golick (James)
	Quotes of Contempt (Joseph)
	Your Logical Fallacy Is Poster (Joseph)
	Winning Arguments: From Aristotle to Obama - Everything You Need to Know about the Art of Persuasion by Jay Heinrichs (Joseph)
	Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andrew Hunt (Joseph)

Homework

Watch the first ten minutes of YouTube | Growing a Language by Guy Steele.
Book Club
The Rails View by John Athayde and Bruce Williams: Read along with us! We will be discussing the book with John and Bruce and the episode will air on Wednesday, May 8th, 2013.
Next Week
Rogues Only: The Care and Feeding of Ruby Gems
Transcript


JOSEPH:  Arguing with an Engineer is like wrestling with a pig in mud. After a while, you realize the pig is enjoying it.

[Laughter]



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by The Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

JAMES:  Hello everybody, and welcome to Ruby Rogues. This is Episode 102. And I will be your host today. I'm James Edward Gray II. With me today are, Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Hello.

JAMES:  David Brady.

DAVID:  Hello and welcome!

JAMES:  Avid Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello, hello!

JAMES:  And today, we have a special guest, Joseph Wilk. Joseph, since this is your first time on here, why don’t you introduce your self?

JOSEPH:  Yeah. Hi, as you said, my name is Joseph Wilk. I've been messing around with Ruby the last ten years or so. And I've been doing a lot of work and looking into Rhetoric and how that helps us in development.

JAMES:  So, I guess we’ll start with the super obvious question. Rhetoric is a new programming language that we’re all going to be using soon?

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:06:02</itunes:duration>
        <media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR102Rhetoric.mp3" fileSize="63384911" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/102-rr-rhetoric-with-joseph-wilk/</feedburner:origLink>
</item>