<item>
		<title>103 RR Ruby Gems</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/K1Ctgya3o7k/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/103-rr-ruby-gems/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1305</guid>
		<description>Panel Josh Susser (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:22 &amp;#8211; Ruby Gems RubyGems.org 03:13 &amp;#8211; Should you build a gem? Daniel Huckstep (@darkhelmetlive) Ruby Batteries Included [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/K1Ctgya3o7k" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/103-rr-ruby-gems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR103Gems.mp3" length="81256411" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) - Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:22 - Ruby Gems


	RubyGems.org

03:13 - Should you build a gem?


	Daniel Huckstep (@darkhelmetlive)
	Ruby Batteries Included by Daniel Huckstep
	trollop

08:12 - Naming Gems


	gem-love
	dash vs underscore
	Eric Hodel: How to Name Gems

16:43 - Tools


	Bundler
	hoe
	jeweler
	What is a gem? - RubyGems Guides
	require_relative

32:50 - Gem Extensions


	autotest-growl

34:39 - Dependencies and Using Bundler to develop gems


	RubyGems Guides
	Gemspec
	TourBus Gem
	TourBus Gemspec File
	TourBus Build File
	jeweler
	hoe
	votes.io

49:35 - How the gemspec gets used in the lifecycle of gem development


	Rakefile for highline

56:20 - Versioning


	037 RR Versioning and Releases

59:00 - Open-Source Licence


	075 RR Open Source Licenses

59:59 - Signing Gems
01:01:25 - Using the packaging system as a dependency


	isolate

01:04:21 - Maintaining Gems


	051 RR Getting Started with Open Source
	Highline
	FasterCSV

01:07:44 - rakegem
01:08:33 - Gem Plugins


	gem-open

Picks

	Joy of Cooking (Josh)
	Gather - the Art of Paleo Entertaining (Josh)
	Erik Dietrich: How Developers Stop Learning: Rise of the Expert Beginner (Avdi)
	Erik Dietrich: How Software Groups Rot: Legacy of the Expert Beginner (Avdi)
	Play by Play: Refactoring with Ben Orenstein | PeepCode Screencasts (James)
	Budget Bytes (James)
	6PM.com (Avdi)
	How To Survive a Ground-Up Rewrite Without Losing Your Sanity aka Screw You, Joel Spolsky, We're Rewriting It From Scratch by Dan Milstein (Guest Post on Dharmesh Shah's OnStartups blog) (David)
	OpenWest Conference (David)
	TEKTON 6235 Assorted Cable Ties, 200-Piece (Chuck)

Next Week
Book Club: The Rails View by John Athayde and Bruce Williams
Transcript
AVDI:  Have you tried just having a cat catcher on your desk?



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by The Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

CHUCK:  Hey everybody, and welcome to Episode 103 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. Does that bother you, Josh? Or should I say a hundred and three?

JOSH:  As long as it’s a cardinal instead of an ordinal, I'm fine.

CHUCK:  Okay.

[Laughter]

CHUCK:  We can't even get started. Alright. This week on our panel, we have Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Hey, good morning everyone from your unreasonably pathetic…never mind!

[Laughter]

CHUCK:  We also have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Good morning, everyone.

CHUCK:  Avid Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello from Pennsylvania.

CHUCK:  David Brady.

DAVID:  We control the vertical and the horizontal which makes no freaking sense on a podcast.

CHUCK:  And I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.tv. And this week, we’re going to be talking about Ruby Gems.

JAMES:  Woohoo!

JOSH:  It’s going to be that kind of episode.

CHUCK:  So Josh, can we get a definition?

JOSH:  Oh, yeah…no.

[Laughter]

JOSH:  If you don’t know what a Ruby Gem is, I'm sorry we can't help you.

CHUCK:  [Laughs]

JAMES:  What was the old competitor, the RPA? Was it RPA?

AVDI:  Oh, man!

DAVID:  Oh! Was it RPA, the Ruby Project Archive?

[Crosstalk]

DAVID:  …after Gems was up. But that was back when you actually had to ask Dave for permission to create a gem. You actually…

JOSH:  Okay. Let’s not get lost in the weeds here.

DAVID:  Yeah.

AVDI:  RAA is the one.

JAMES:  Not RAA. Not that.

JOSH:  Okay. So, Ruby Gems are the best software packaging system in the universe. That’s the definition.

CHUCK:  Yehey!

[Laughter]

DAVID:  Open keyboard.

JAMES:  Well, there what we got.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:24:39</itunes:duration>
        <media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR103Gems.mp3" fileSize="81256411" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/103-rr-ruby-gems/</feedburner:origLink>

    </item>