<item>
		<title>086 RR Learning From The Past with Arlen Walker</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/Rgxa3ZmsbOw/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/086-rr-learning-from-the-past-with-arlen-walker/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arlen Walker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1007</guid>
		<description>Panel Arlen Walker (twitter blog) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Discussion 01:57 &amp;#8211; Arlen Walker Introduction PKWARE, Inc. 03:06 &amp;#8211; Unofficial Rogue: Dave Newton 03:49 &amp;#8211; Best of Parley: DHH episode 056 RR David Heinemeier Hansson 05:33 &amp;#8211; [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/Rgxa3ZmsbOw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/086-rr-learning-from-the-past-with-arlen-walker/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR086LearningFromThePast.mp3" length="63766103" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Arlen Walker (twitter blog)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) - Discussion 01:57 - Arlen Walker Introduction - </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Arlen Walker (twitter blog)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)

Discussion
01:57 - Arlen Walker Introduction

	PKWARE, Inc.

03:06 - Unofficial Rogue: Dave Newton

03:49 - Best of Parley: DHH episode

	056 RR David Heinemeier Hansson

05:33 - Vote for your favorite Ruby Rogues Episode of 2012:


rubyrogues.com/survey

05:58 - Learning From The Past


On Chess and Software Development by Arlen Walker
	Model-view-controller

10:15 - Learning From The Rules

	Chess
	047 RR Coding Disciplines with Dan Kubb

17:01 - Testing/Best Practices

	Head First books
	Head First Design Patterns By Eric Freeman, Elisabeth Robson, Bert Bates, Kathy Sierra

23:39 - Mentoring

	Pair Programming

25:49 - Learning From Other People’s Mistakes


Code Reading: The Open Source Perspective by Diomidis Spinellis

Software Tools by Brian W. Kernighan, P.J. Plauger
	Planning for the future; doing nothing

33:11 - Learning &amp; Teaching Concepts

	The Gang of Four Book
	Skill Acquisition: The Dreyfus Model

Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andy Hunt
	The Desire to Learn

47:50 - Good Introductory Patterns


Sugar-Free Ruby: An Experiment in Object-first: Steven! Regnarök

The Composed Method

Adapter Pattern

Facade Pattern

Factory Method Pattern

Picks

	Lost Treasures of Infocom (David)
	Kyocera Mega Peeler (Katrina)
	Daemon by Daniel Suarez (Katrina)
	Freedom by Daniel Suarez (Katrina)
	Press Enter by John Varley (Josh)
	Cake Wrecks (Josh)
	Middleman (Josh)
	tcrayford / Values (James)
	solnic / virtus (James)
	The Verge at work: backing up your brain (How I use Evernote as a memory tool for deep  reading, writing, and research) by Thomas Houston (James)
	Guide to Good Chess by C.J.S. Purdy (Arlen)
	The Search for Chess Perfection by C.J.S. Purdy (Arlen)
	Yusupov’s award-winning Training Course (Arlen)
	O’Reilly - Safari Books Online (Arlen)
	The Lurker’s Guide to Babylon 5 (Arlen)

Next Week
Book Club Episode: Sandi Metz - Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby: An Agile Primer
Transcript
JOSH:  Okay, don’t tell the world, but I’m having headset issues today.

JAMES: I’m having Skype issues; like, my mute button has apparently…

[Laughter]

KATRINA: That was beautiful.

ARLEN: Poetic.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.]

[This episode is sponsored by Jet Brains, makers of Ruby Mine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built-in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out Ruby Mine by going to JetBrains.com/ruby]

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic]

JAMES: Hey everybody and welcome to the Ruby Rouges podcast. Chuck is off this week, so I’ll be your host. With me today, I have David Brady.

DAVID: 404 Poop metaphor not found.

JAMES:  Josh Susser.

JOSH: Good Morning!

JAMES: Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Good afternoon or evening from the Arctic!

JAMES: And we have a guest Rogue this week, Arlen Walker.

ARLEN: The button today is, “Mr. Garibaldi, get that police box out of my office, now!”

JOSH:  Very nice. James, I know you don’t run the show very often, but you forgot to mention yourself in the introductions.

JAMES: Oh yeah. I am James Edward Gray, the second, who doesn’t run the show often enough to remember how to do an intro.

DAVID:  Today, we’re talking about ‘off by one errors’.

JAMES: But today, the good news is I reclaim my tie for most episodes of Ruby Rogues recordings, so it’s a very special day. We have some announcements to make before we get into the show proper. Actually before we do that, Arlen,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:06:25</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR086LearningFromThePast.mp3" fileSize="63766103" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/086-rr-learning-from-the-past-with-arlen-walker/</feedburner:origLink></item>