<item>
		<title>105 RR Regular Expressions with Nell Shamrell</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/_5xnoN6tmGA/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/105-rr-regular-expressions-with-nell-shamrell/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nell Shamrell]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1330</guid>
		<description>Panel Nell Shamrell (twitter github) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:33 &amp;#8211; DevChat.tv Indiegogo Campaign 02:16 &amp;#8211; Nell Shamrell Introduction Blue Box Nell Shamrell: Using [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/_5xnoN6tmGA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/105-rr-regular-expressions-with-nell-shamrell/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR105RegularExpressions.mp3" length="78651719" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Nell Shamrell (twitter github)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rail...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Nell Shamrell (twitter github)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:33 - DevChat.tv Indiegogo Campaign
02:16 - Nell Shamrell Introduction


	Blue Box
	Nell Shamrell: Using Regular Expressions in Ruby (Part 1 of 3)
	Nell Shamrell: Using Regular Expressions in Ruby (Part 2 of 3)
	Nell Shamrell: Using Regular Expressions in Ruby (Part 3 of 3)

03:11 - Regular Expressions


	Regular Language

08:38 - Being intimidated by Regular Expressions


	Beyond the Basics: Regular Expressions in Ruby (Nell’s Seattle.rb SlideShare Presentation)
	Oniguruma Regular Expressions Version 5.9.1
	Rubular

14:54 - Managing Regular Expressions
15:51 - Regular Expression Gotchas


	sub and gsub
	regex speed
	O'Reilly Media: Mastering Regular Expressions by Jeffrey E.F. Friedl
	Anchoring

20:39 - Possessive, Greedy and Lazy Quantifiers
24:10 - Lookaheads, Lookbehinds and Lookarounds


	scan

28:21 - Regular Expression Engines


	PCRE

31:56 - Ruby-Specific ways of working with regular expressions


	match
	Capture Groups
	Magic Globals
	Oniguruma
	Onigmo
	grep
	rindex

47:02 - What shouldn’t you use regular expressions for?


	include?
	start_with?
	html - RegEx match open tags except XHTML self-contained tags - Stack Overflow
	Mail::RFC822::Address: regexp-based address validation

51:09 - Substitutions


	Escapes &amp; Escaping
	%r
	O'Reilly Media: The Ruby Programming Language by David Flanagan, Yukihiro Matsumoto

01:00:37 - Regex xkcd Comics


	xkcd | Regular Expressions
	xkcd | 1171: Perl Problems

01:02:51 - Tricks


	Lea Verou: /Reg(exp){2}lained/: Demystifying Regular Expressions
	StringScanner
	split

Picks

	GOG.com (James)
	Master of Orion 1+2 (James)
	Starbase Orion (James)
	xkcd: I Know Regular Expressions T-Shirt (Josh)
	s/teh/the/ (Josh)
	Brakeman (Katrina)
	rx (Avdi)
	Re Builder (Avdi)
	Southwest Airlines (Avdi)
	StarCraft II (Chuck)
	Continuum (Chuck)
	Pat Shaughnessy: Exploring Ruby’s Regular Expression Algorithm (Nell)
	Lea Verou: /Reg(exp){2}lained/: Demystifying Regular Expressions (Nell)
	Naginata (Nell)

Book Club
Explore It!: Reduce Risk and Increase Confidence with Exploratory Testing by Elisabeth Hendrickson! We will be recording with Elisabeth on June 19th, 2013 and the episode will air on June 26th.
Next Week
Discourse with Jeff Atwood
Transcript
JAMES:  We aren’t always good about passing the ball around. So, if you have something to say, speak up.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at Bluebox.net.] 

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built-in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to jetBrains.com/Ruby.] 

[This show is sponsored by Heroku Postgres. They’re the largest provider of Postgres databases in the world and provide the ability for you to fork and follow your database, just like your code. There's easy sharing through data clips or just for your data. And to date, they have never lost a byte of data. So, go and sign up at Postgres.Heroku.com.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

CHUCK:  Hey everybody, and welcome to Episode 105 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Yey, regex!

CHUCK:  We also have Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello from jetlag.

CHUCK:  Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Hello from jetlag’s neighbor.

CHUCK:  Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Good morning from San Francisco.

CHUCK:  I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.tv.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:21:56</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR105RegularExpressions.mp3" fileSize="78651719" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/105-rr-regular-expressions-with-nell-shamrell/</feedburner:origLink></item>