<item>
		<title>107 RR Impostor Syndrome with Tim Chevalier</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/107-rr-impostor-syndrome-with-tim-chevalier/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/107-rr-impostor-syndrome-with-tim-chevalier/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Chevalier]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1347</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Tim Chevalier (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:32 &#8211; Tim Chevalier Introduction Research Engineer at Mozilla Rust Geek Feminism Blog Tim’s Dreamwidth Journal Impostor Syndrome: Part [...]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/107-rr-impostor-syndrome-with-tim-chevalier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR107ImpostorSyndrome.mp3" length="71001392" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Tim Chevalier (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) - Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Tim Chevalier (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:32 - Tim Chevalier Introduction


	Research Engineer at Mozilla
	Rust
	Geek Feminism Blog
	Tim’s Dreamwidth Journal
	Impostor Syndrome: Part 1 of 4
	Impostor Syndrome: Part 2 of 4
	Impostor Syndrome: Part 3 of 4
	Impostor Syndrome: Part 4 of 4

02:01 - Impostor Syndrome
05:16 - Marginalized groups and Impostor Syndrome


	Stereotype Threat
	“I don’t belong here”

08:13 - Keeping score and comparing yourself to others
11:05 - Identifying people with Impostor Syndrome


	Self-deprecation
	Withdrawing

13:50 - Unfalsifiable Beliefs


	Evidence
	Reinforcement

21:33 - Don't Tell Your Kids They’re ‘Smart’
28:42 - Helping yourself overcome Impostor Syndrome


	Values &amp; Beliefs
	Acknowledging when you’re wrong
	Feedback
	Working hard at something difficult and making progress
	Brené Brown: The power of vulnerability

34:55 - Affirmations


	Evaluating strengths and weaknesses

40:16 - Helping others overcome Impostor Syndrome


	Ask them to help you with something
	Praise

43:50 - Isolation &amp; Inclusion
45:11 - Combating Impostor Syndrome


	Cognitive Behavioral Therapy
	Acknowledgement and Acceptance
	Humor &amp; Joking

Picks

	CrashPlan (Avdi)
	Hyperbole and a Half: Depression Part Two (Katrina)
	Angela Lee Duckworth: The key to success? Grit (Katrina)
	AngularJS (David)
	three.js (David)
	The Feeling Good Handbook by David. D. Burns (David)
	You Can’t Afford the Luxury of a Negative Thought by Peter McWilliams (David)
	iOctocat (Chuck)
	iOctocat on GitHub (Chuck)
	OmniFocus (Chuck)
	The UNIX-HATERS Handbook (Tim)
	It's okay for someone else to be wrong (Tim)

Book Club
Explore It!: Reduce Risk and Increase Confidence with Exploratory Testing by Elisabeth Hendrickson! We will be recording with Elisabeth on June 19th, 2013 and the episode will air on June 26th.
Next Week
Rogues Only Episode
Transcript
DAVID: Did somebody say ‘poop joke’?



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at Bluebox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

[This show is sponsored by Heroku Postgres. They’re the largest provider of Postgres databases in the world and provide the ability for you to fork and follow your database, just like your code. There's easy sharing through data clips or just for your data. And to date, they have never lost a byte of data. So, go and sign up at Postgres.Heroku.com.] 

 [This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built-in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to JetBrains.com/Ruby.] 

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to Episode 107 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Hello.

CHUCK:  Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello.

CHUCK:  David Brady. I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.tv and I’m going to be impostoring both Josh Susser and James Edward Gray today. We also have a special guest and that is Tim Chevalier.  Is it [she-va-lee-ay]?

TIM:  [Sheva-lee-ay].

CHUCK:  [Sheva-lee-ay]. It’s French.

TIM:  It is.

CHUCK:  Looks French-ish, so I said it French-ish, I guess. Anyway, do you want to introduce yourself really quick?

TIM:  Sure. My name’s Tim Chevalier. And right now, I’m a Research Engineer at Mozilla. I work on the Rust programming language, but in my copious free time, I blog at  HYPERLINK "http://www.GeekFeminism.org" www.GeekFeminism.org and on Dreamwidth about the social aspects of tech, especially diversity and intrasectionality.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:13:58</itunes:duration>
	</item>