<item>
		<title>109 RR Extreme Programming with Will Read</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/109-rr-extreme-programming-with-will-read/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/109-rr-extreme-programming-with-will-read/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Read]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1361</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Will Read (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 02:26 &#8211; Will Read Introduction Pivotal Labs 03:11 &#8211; Extreme Programming (XP) &#38; Development Practices Pair Programming Test-Driven Development [...]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/109-rr-extreme-programming-with-will-read/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR109ExtremeProgramming.mp3" length="73410493" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Will Read (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) - Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Will Read (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
02:26 - Will Read Introduction


	Pivotal Labs

03:11 - Extreme Programming (XP) &amp; Development Practices


	Pair Programming
	Test-Driven Development (TDD)
	Continuous Integration
	Frequent Deploys
	Extreme Programming Explained: Embrace Change, Second Edition by Kent Beck

05:00 - Manifesto for Agile Software Development


	Scrum
	Kanban

07:22 - Project Management Practices


	Iteration Planning
	Retrospectives
	Stand-ups
	SalesForce

09:07 - Purpose and Attractiveness of XP


	Reinforcement
	Feedback Loops
	“How do we get better?”

17:56 - Pair Programming (Particular Practices)
21:09 - Team Structure


	Conway’s Law
	Ruby Conf 2012 - The Insufficiency of Good Design by Sarah Mei
	Customer Product Manager (PM)
	Collocation

23:54 - Remote Pair Programming


	#pairwithme
	MadEye
	Tmux
	Screenhero
	Wide Teams

29:22 - Hiring People for XP
30:56 - Sustainable Pace


	Extreme Programming Rules
	Pivotal Tracker
	Discipline

37:27 - Design


	Designer/Developer Disconnect

43:11 - QA (Quality Assurance) Teams


	Explore It!: Reduce Risk and Increase Confidence with Exploratory Testing by Elisabeth Hendrickson

45:55 - When XP is a bad thing
47:46 - Team Size
51:21 - Tools


	Introducing the Style Guide Gem - Doc Ritezel
	git-duet
	Jenkins CI
	ciborg

52:50 - Physical Workstations


	Desk Setup
	Pairing tete-a-tete - Pivotal Labs
	Team-owned Machines

56:44 - Resources


	Extreme Programming Explained: Embrace Change, Second Edition by Kent Beck
	Pivotal Labs Blog
	Dev Bootcamp

Picks

	EP398: Subversion - Escape Pod (Avdi)
	The Room (Avdi)
	Rails Girls Summer of Code (James)
	LoneStar Ruby (James)
	Tiassa (Vlad Taltos) by Steven Brust (Josh)
	Commit (Chuck)
	The Crucible (Will)
	Pivotal Labs Blog (Will)
	Dev Bootcamp (Will)

Book Club
Explore It!: Reduce Risk and Increase Confidence with Exploratory Testing by Elisabeth Hendrickson! We will be recording with Elisabeth on June 19th, 2013 and the episode will air on June 26th.
Next Week
ActiveRecord with Ernie Miller
Transcript
AVDI: We’re talking about Windows XP today, right?

CHUCK:  Yeah.

JAMES:  That’s it. Windows XP. [Chuckles]

WILL:  Yeah. That’s why we’re using Skype.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at Bluebox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

[This show is sponsored by Heroku Postgres. They’re the largest provider of Postgres databases in the world and provide the ability for you to fork and follow your database, just like your code. There's easy sharing through data clips or just for your data. And to date, they have never lost a byte of data. So, go and sign up at Postgres.Heroku.com.] 

 [This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built-in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to jetBrains.com/Ruby.] 

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to Ruby Rogues Episode 109. Before we get started, I just want to make sure that you know, many of you have complained that we don’t have all of our episodes in the backlog. I am fixing that. About half of you have moved over to the original feed, but half of you are still stuck on Feed Burner. I’m going to turn off the Feed Burner feed after this episode is released. It should redirect you to the new feed. But if you don’t get any episodes after that, keep that in mind and please re-subscribe in iTunes. That’s my big announcement.

JAMES:  We’re going away?

CHUCK:  Well.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
	</item>