<item>
		<title>096 RR Topaz with Alex Gaynor</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/_teqRm6oNN8/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/096-rr-topaz-with-alex-gaynor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 13:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Alex Gaynor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1189</guid>
		<description>Panel Alex Gaynor (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:30 &amp;#8211; Alex Gaynor Introduction Rdio Topaz Python 01:54 &amp;#8211; Combining Python and Ruby Announcing Topaz: A New Ruby &amp;#8211; [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/_teqRm6oNN8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/096-rr-topaz-with-alex-gaynor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR096Topaz.mp3" length="53941955" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel   Alex Gaynor (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel


	Alex Gaynor (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)


Discussion
01:30 - Alex Gaynor Introduction



Rdio


Topaz


Python


01:54 - Combining Python and Ruby

	Announcing Topaz: A New Ruby - Topaz 0.1 documentation
	RPython

PyPy


DJango


05:57 - Websites that run on DJango

	addons.mozilla.org/
	DISQUS

06:38 - Running Topaz

	Squeak
	ANSI C

09:15 - TopazWroclove2013: Tim Felgentreff


Maglev


13:44 - Compilation Errors


15:10 - Integration with Ruby

	RubySpec
	Rubinius
	lib-topaz

17:47 - Performance and Benchmarking


20:52 - Global Interpreter Lock


Waiting to implement features


23:26 - Design Goals

	Simplicity
	Performance

26:10 - Worst Part of the Ruby Language

	Complexity of constant lookups
	Number of different scopes

28:40 - Why Python, Ruby, and Javascript are Slow by Alex Gaynor


35:16 - Where is Topaz now/Where will it be in the future?


Pull requests


FFI


Targeting specs

	PLY (Python Lex-Yacc)

44:20 - Ruby features that people use wrong


46:23 - Blocks

Picks


	Tattoo yourself with electronic circuits - Crave Culture (Katrina)
	iTextEditors - iPhone and iPad text/code editors and writing tools compared (James)
	Textastic (James)
	Nebulous Notes (James)
	The Top 25 iPhone and iPad Games - IGN (James)
	The Best 50 iOS Games of 2012 | Slide To Play (James)
	Outwitters (James)
	rumblelabs / asset_sync (Josh)
	Powers Bureau Comic (Josh)
	strftimer (Josh)
	Synergy (Chuck)
	astrails / safe (Chuck)
	Fair Play by Steven E. Landsburg (Alex)
	Werkzeug (The Python WSGI Utility Library) (Alex)
	Gender Through the Prism of Difference by Michael A. Messner (Alex)

Book Club
Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture by Martin Fowler: You have one week left to finish it! Yay!
Next Week
Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture with Martin Fowler
Transcript
JOSH:  And I'm also drinking my coffee from an Aperture Science mug.

JAMES:  Wow!

JOSH:  Yeah.

JAMES:  Wow! Alright, you win! You're the geekiest!

JOSH:  [Chuckles] Well, right now.

JAMES:  [Chuckles] Yeah, right now.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to Episode 96 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Hello from Denver.

CHUCK:  James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  It’s time to take off your gem-crested boots and put on your hat with that cool slick thing.

CHUCK:  Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Next time, make me go first because I never know how to follow anybody anymore.

[Laughter]

CHUCK:  Especially with gem-crested boots and a hat band, right?

JOSH:  Yeah, I don’t even know where that came from.

[Laughter]

JOSH:  But good morning!

CHUCK:  I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.tv. And this week, we have a special guest. And that’s Alex Gaynor.

ALEX:  Hi! I was not told I need clever introductions.

JAMES:  [Laughs] Well, you came up with one anyway.

JOSH:  Alex, I've been doing this for over a year and I still don’t have one.

CHUCK:  [Laughs] So, you want to introduce your self really quickly, Alex?

ALEX:  Sure. So, my name is Alex. I live in San Francisco. I am primarily a Python programmer. I work for a company called Rdio.com. We do streaming Internet music. And I guess I'm here because I wrote a thing called Topaz which is a Ruby VM written in Python.

JAMES:  [Chuckles] So, I guess the obvious question to follow is, why?

JOSH:  [Laughs]

ALEX:  Well, first and foremost, because it was a lot of fun.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>56:11</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR096Topaz.mp3" fileSize="53941955" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/096-rr-topaz-with-alex-gaynor/</feedburner:origLink></item>