<item>
		<title>097 RR Book Club: Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture with Martin Fowler</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/hNPBLCxVlTU/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/097-rr-book-club-patterns-of-enterprise-architecture-with-martin-fowler/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Martin Fowler]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1203</guid>
		<description>Panel Martin Fowler (twitter martinfowler.com) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Discussion 01:31 &amp;#8211; Martin Fowler Introduction “Author, speaker and general loud-mouth on the topic of software development” martinfowler.com 02:05 &amp;#8211; Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture by Martin Fowler [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/hNPBLCxVlTU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/097-rr-book-club-patterns-of-enterprise-architecture-with-martin-fowler/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR097POEAA.mp3" length="98158318" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel   Martin Fowler (twitter martinfowler.com)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel


	Martin Fowler (twitter martinfowler.com)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)


Discussion
01:31 - Martin Fowler Introduction



	“Author, speaker and general loud-mouth on the topic of software development”
	martinfowler.com




02:05 - Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture by Martin Fowler (PoEAA)

	Programming Ruby 1.9: The Pragmatic Programmers’ Guide by Andy Hunt (The Pickaxe Book)
	Transform View

10:47 - Architecture

12:30 - Patterns

	The Timeless Way of Building by Christopher Alexander 
	Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software by Erich Gamma, Richard Helm, Ralph Johnson &amp; John Vlissides (Gang of Four Book)
	Domain-Specific Languages by Martin Fowler
	Portland Pattern Repository

21:51 - Jargon




25:17 - Code of Ethics &amp; Authority

29:08 - Rails




	The five programming books that meant most to me by David Heinemeier Hansson of 37 Signals

34:09 - Growing/Evolving Patterns

	Active record pattern
	Data mapper pattern
	Identity Map

42:55 - NoSQL

	NoSQL Distilled: A Brief Guide to the Emerging World of Polyglot Persistence by Martin Fowler
	Aggregate pattern
	Ruby DataMapper Status | solnic.eu

49:59 - Row Data Gateway

56:52 - Potential Book Updates

01:00:23 - Service-oriented Architecture

	Enterprise Integration Patterns: Designing, Building, and Deploying Messaging Solutions by Gregor Hohpe and Bobby Woolf

01:05:45 - Service Layer

01:14:00 - Remote Facade Pattern

01:19:55 - UniformAccessPrincipal

	Ruby Tapas Episode 4: Barewords

01:22:28 - PoEAA for Beginners

	Dreyfus model of skill acquisition
	Mocks Aren’t Stubs: Martin Fowler

01:26:28 - Martin’s Next Book Club Book Suggestion

	Domain-Driven Design: Tackling in the Heart of Software by Eric Evans


Picks


	Pinoccio (Katrina)
	Corsair Vengeance 2000 Wireless Gaming Headset (Avdi)
	White Tea (Avdi)
	Growing A Language by Guy Steele (Josh)
	Backup your data (Josh)
	The Better Angels of Our Nature: Why Violence Has Declined by Steven Pinker (James)
	SourceTree (Martin)
	jq (Martin)
	Thinking, Fast and Slow by Daniel Kahneman (Martin)
	Jekyll (Martin)

Book Club
The Rails View by John Athayde and Bruce Williams: Read along with us! We will be discussing the book with John and Bruce and the episode will air on Wednesday, May 8th, 2013.
Next Week
DRb with Davy Stevenson
Transcript
JAMES:  I will try to start us off here, I think.

JOSH:  James, do you have your smelling salts handy?

[Laughter]

JAMES:  Selling salts: I’ve been dosing myself regularly.

[Laughter]

AVDI:  Now, you have a resistance to smelling salts.

JOSH:  Wait! Does that work like Iocane powder?

[Laughter]



[Hosting and bandwidth was provided by The Blue Box Group, check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

JAMES:  Hello everyone and welcome to the 97th episode of the Ruby Rogues podcast. Uh, oh! I think I said 97th. Josh prefers it when I say Episode 97 of the Ruby Rogues podcast.

Chuck’s out today sick, we’re very sorry. We hope that he feels better soon. David Brady is out today and we have no idea what he’s doing but the rest of us are here. I’ll be your host James Gray and with me today is Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello from Pennsylvania.

JAMES:  Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Yes, I took a correspondence course in Pedantics.

[Laughter]

JAMES:  And Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Hello from Colorado.

JAMES:  And also with us today is special guest, Martin Fowler.

MARTIN:  Hello from melting Boston.

JAMES:  Martin, this is the first time you’ve been on this show. So, for the one person out there who doesn’t know who you are, why don’t you introduce your self?

MARTIN:  Okay,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:42:15</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR097POEAA.mp3" fileSize="98158318" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/097-rr-book-club-patterns-of-enterprise-architecture-with-martin-fowler/</feedburner:origLink></item>