<item>
		<title>098 RR DRb with Davy Stevenson</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/ngIFzTXuH2o/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/098-rr-drb-with-davy-stevenson/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Davy Stevenson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1245</guid>
		<description>Panel Davy Stevenson (twitter github) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:02 &amp;#8211; Davy Stevenson Introduction Elemental Technologies DRb vs RabbitMQ Showdown &amp;#8211; Davy Stevenson &amp;#8211; [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/ngIFzTXuH2o" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/098-rr-drb-with-davy-stevenson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR098DRb.mp3" length="58983379" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Davy Stevenson (twitter github)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rai...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Davy Stevenson (twitter github)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:02 - Davy Stevenson Introduction


	Elemental Technologies
	DRb vs RabbitMQ Showdown - Davy Stevenson - Ruby Conference 2012

03:29 - dRuby


	dRuby Definition
	Multiprogramming

06:09 - DRb style of programming
09:18 - DRb across multiple machines
10:28 - Distributed Objects


	097 RR Book Club: Patterns of Enterprise Architecture with Martin Fowler
	Signaling Mechanism
	GOOS: Growing Object-Oriented Software by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce

17:22 - Passing data through DRb


	Calling Methods
	Daemon Process

20:58 - RabbitMQ


	Rinda and Rinda::Ring
	Class: Ring::RingFinger (Ruby 1.9.3)

25:50 - Reliability


	James: DRb is definitely a hacker's tool.
	Eric Hodel: I'm considering writing drbdump, a tcpdump equivalent.

30:20 - Durability
33:39 - Concurrency Issues
38:23 - DRb Magic


	Marshalling
	Remote Facade Pattern

45:13 - Getting started with DRb


	seki / Drip
	The dRuby Book: Distributed and Parallel Computing with Ruby by Masatoshi Seki (Translated by Makoto Inoue)
	Distributed Programming with Ruby by Mark Bates

48:13 - DRb Use

Picks

	CloudFlare (Avdi)
	Adam Sanderson: Getting to Know the Ruby Standard Library - TSort (James)
	Homeschooling Makes Me Happy: Logan LaPlante at TEDxUniversityofNevada (James)
	Raspberry Jamboree 2013: Amy Mather - Conway's Game Of Life (James)
	Errplane (Josh)
	Version Badge for your RubyGems, PyPI packages, and NPM modules (Josh)
	Scott Kim Inversions (Josh)
	Regex Puzzle (Katrina)
	Hazel (Chuck)
	Amazon S3 (Chuck)
	The dRuby Book: Distributed and Parallel Computing with Ruby by Masatoshi Seki (Translated by Makoto Inoue) (Davy)
	reveal.js - The HTML Presentation Framework (Davy)
	"The Ancestor" by Darlingside  (Davy)

Book Club
The Rails View by John Athayde and Bruce Williams: Read along with us! We will be discussing the book with John and Bruce and the episode will air on Wednesday, May 8th, 2013.

Next Week
Rogues Only Episode: Ruby 2

Transcript


JAMES:  Alright. So, we’re talking about some DRb today?

DAVY:  That’s the plan.

CHUCK:  Derb…



[Hosting and bandwidth was provided by The Blue Box Group, check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to Episode 98 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Good morning, everybody.

CHUCK:  Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Hey, good morning from San Francisco.

CHUCK:  Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Hello from Denver.

CHUCK:  Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello from Pennsylvania.

CHUCK:  I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.tv. I'm looking forward to hearing about Distributed Regexes. We also have a special guest and that’s Davy Stevenson. I can't see your last name on here.

DAVY:  That’s Davy Stevenson. I'm from Portland, Oregon.

CHUCK:  Alright. You want to introduce yourself really quickly since you haven't been on the show before?

DAVY:  Sure. So, I worked for a company called Elemental Technologies up in Portland, Oregon. We do video transcoding software. I have been coding Ruby on Rails for, let’s see, 2008 to 2013. So that’s, if I can do math correctly, five years.

JAMES:  Awesome.

JOSH:  That’s really cool. And you did a talk at RubyConf last year, right?

DAVY:  Yes, I did. That was my first big talk at a conference. And it was on DRb and RabbitMQ.

JOSH:  Yeah. That was a good talk. I watched the video for it. Unfortunately, I missed it when I was in Denver. But it was a good talk. I liked it.

JAMES:  It was a good talk.

DAVY:  Well, thank you.

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:01:26</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR098DRb.mp3" fileSize="58983379" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/098-rr-drb-with-davy-stevenson/</feedburner:origLink></item>