<item>
		<title>RR 061 Domain Driven Design (DDD) with David Laribee</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/rr-061-domain-driven-design-ddd-with-david-laribee/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/rr-061-domain-driven-design-ddd-with-david-laribee/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Laribee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=587</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel David Laribee (twitter github laribee.com) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp) James Edward Gray II (blog twitter github) Discussion Domain Driven Design Domain Model Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture by Martin Fowler Domain Driven Design by Eric Evans Growing Object Oriented Software Guided by Tests Eric Evans Ubiquitous Language &#8211; use the [...]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/rr-061-domain-driven-design-ddd-with-david-laribee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR061DDD.mp3" length="73300316" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  David Laribee (twitter github laribee.com)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp)   James Edward Gray II (blog twitter github) - Discussion  Domain Driven Design   Do...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	David Laribee (twitter github laribee.com)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp)
	James Edward Gray II (blog twitter github)

Discussion

	Domain Driven Design
	Domain Model
	Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture by Martin Fowler
	Domain Driven Design by Eric Evans
	Growing Object Oriented Software Guided by Tests
	Eric Evans
	Ubiquitous Language - use the terms the business/users use in your code
	Bounded Context
	the Pattern Language
	Repository - Allows you to retrieve things
	Entity - Something with an identity
	Refactoring
	TDD (Test Driven Development)
	SOA (Service Oriented Architecture)
	MSDN article on DDD
	Wikipedia page on DDD
	Podcast interview with David on DDD Part 1, Part 2
	Anti-corruption layer
	Smalltalk Best Practice Patterns by Kent Beck
	Ruby Rogues review of Smalltalk Best Practice Patterns
	Ruby Rogues follow up episode to SBPP
	Objectified (documentary)
	ActiveRecord (the design pattern)
	ActiveRecord (the Rails library)
	Objects on Rails by Avdi Grimm
	ActiveModel
	Aggregates (Domain Model pattern)
	Domain Specific Languages
	A good DSL has a strong semantic model
	Cucumber
	Gherkin
	Programmers should be good guides and can become domain knowledge experts
	Project glossaries/dictionaries
	Javascript Jabber episode on Agile Development
	DDD leads to simple design
	QCon book
	Spiking code
	The Pragmatic Programmer by Dave Thomas and Andy Hunt

Picks

	James' Math Literacy talk slides (James)
	The Ruby Way by Hal Fulton (Avdi)
	World War II twitter accounts (Avdi)

	realtimewwii
	RosiesWWII


	Daily Sudoku (Chuck)
	Handlebars.js (Chuck)
	Hammock Driven Development (David)
	Exped Ergo Hammock (David)

Transcript 
AVDI: So Linux received a Skype upgrade. I think this one is from 1995.

JAMES: Wow.

CHUCK: Yey!

JAMES: Jeez. So current.



CHUCK: I have the most recent version of it. I think its interface is from 1995.

AVDI: Hahaha!

JAMES: Agree.

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to Rubyrogues.com/newrelic.]

[Hosting provided by Blue Box Group. Check them out at bluebox.net.]

CHUCK: Hey everybody and welcome to Episode 61 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have Avdi Grimm.

AVDI: Hello from sunny Pennsylvania. Just a quick reminder, my other podcast wideteams.com is going strong. I’ve had a ton of interviews with awesome programmers working remotely in a distributed team. So if you do that. Please check it out.

CHUCK: Awesome.

AVDI: Ok, I’m done.

CHUCK: We also have James Edward Grey.

JAMES: I’m mostly dead today. I’m very sick so I will try to contribute between coughing.

CHUCK: Well, if you’re mostly dead that means you’re slightly alive.

JAMES: True. If you’re all dead, you have to go through their pockets and look for those changes.

CHUCK: That’s right. We’re gonna do another princess bride episode. I remember that one; that was fun. We also have a special guest and that’s David Laribee.

DAVID: Hello! Coming at you from Hotlanta.

CHUCK: “Hotlanta” huh?

JAMES: How hot there?

DAVID: It’s getting hot in here. Something 95F.

CHUCK: Oh was that all?

JAMES: We’ve been over a hundred for three days now.

DAVID: Really? Okay. Well, Temperatelanta.

CHUCK: [laughs] You wanna introduce yourself, David? From those who don’t know who you are.

DAVID: Sure. I work for VersionOne. I work in a product development team. I am the development coach. Kinda like a tech lead, I suppose. I’ve been developing myself for 15 years, across a wide variety of industries. Mostly lately have been in the Ruby and JavaScript kinda world. So, polyglot. I do conference speaking,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:01:05</itunes:duration>
	</item>