<item>
		<title>059 RR – Security with Rein Henrichs</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/059-rr-security-with-rein-henrichs/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/059-rr-security-with-rein-henrichs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rein Henrichs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Rein Henrichs (twitter github reinh.com) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp) James Edward Gray II (blog twitter github) Discussion Ruby on Ales As a site is on the internet longer, it&#8217;s probability of being hacked approaches 1. Don&#8217;t underestimate the risks of being hacked. Loss of revenue, legal liability, and loss of reputation are [...]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/059-rr-security-with-rein-henrichs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR059Security.mp3" length="71690990" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Rein Henrichs (twitter github reinh.com)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp)   James Edward Gray II (blog twitter github) - Discussion  Ruby on Ales </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Rein Henrichs (twitter github reinh.com)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp)
	James Edward Gray II (blog twitter github)

Discussion

	Ruby on Ales
	As a site is on the internet longer, it's probability of being hacked approaches 1.
	Don't underestimate the risks of being hacked.
	Loss of revenue, legal liability, and loss of reputation are some risks.
	SSL
	Think like a "hacker."
	Security is a practice, not a product.
	RailsCasts on Session Hijacking
	FireSheep
	VPN
	How am I storing passwords?
	Bastion hosts
	BCrypt
	Upgrade to 3.2.5 to avoid the SQL injection vulnerability
	Rails vs Sinatra
	Wordpress
	CSRF tokens
	Make a list of the inputs into your system.

	URL bar
	Forms
	API's


	Then look into ways that people can find a way past.
	What do you do when you get hacked?
	Don't keep your compromised system running.
	DDOS attacks
	Always assume the worst case scenario.
	Last.fm compromise
	League of Legends compromise
	You can't count on your users to do the right thing.
	SCrypt
	Password Strength Meters
	What to do when you're hacked:

	Take the affected systems offline
	Keep the affected systems around for forensic analysis
	Once you have a fix that solves the problem, deploy it and then "nuke the effected systems from space."


	Disclose as soon as you know you are hacked.
	Don't try to hide things.
	Get a second opinion on your statement.
	You are not the victim, your users are the victim
	Amazon network outage write-up
	Brute forcing is a numbers game.
	Exponential decay
	Maximum failure lockout
	SQL Injection
	Metasploit
	Professional Penetration Testing
	You can't control how people use your site or disclose vulnerabilities.
	Github public key vulnerability commit
	Don't sell something when you disclose that you were hacked
	Don't be telling your users you're security experts after being hacked
	Security problems are a priority issue that likely originates with management.
	Your job when you get hacked is to protect your users and tell them how to protect yourself.
	The Columbia shuttle disaster was not an engineering failure, it was a culture failure.
	Password generators
	Rails Security Group
	Rails Vulnerability List

Picks

	John Scalzi's recipe for Schadenfreude Pie (Avdi)
	Pronunciation Manual on Youtube (Rein)
	1Password - Mac, iOS (James)
	LastPass
	Emacs (James)
	Paper tray spacers (Chuck)
	MyBook Hard Drive (Chuck)
	ZipKin (Rein)
	Playing Shakespeare (Rein)

Book Club
We're reading Growing Object Oriented Software Guided by Tests for the book club. We'll be reviewing it sometime in August.
Transcript
JAMES: Alright guys, I think I got to go be productive today. You have this job thing, I can’t figure out how to get rid of.

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to rubyrogues.com/newrelic.]

CHUCK: Hey everybody! And welcome to Episode 59 of the Ruby Rogues Podcast. This week on our panel we have Avdi Grimm.



AVDI: Hello from Pennsylvania!

CHUCK: James Edward Grey.

JAMES: Hello from outside of Pennsylvania!

CHUCK: I’m Charles Max Wood from teachmetocode.com. And we also have a special guest, and that’s Rein Henrichs.

REIN: Hello from Portland!

CHUCK: Portland? Awesome.

AVDI: Not bad.

CHUCK: So what do you do in Portland?

REIN: I work for Living Social.

CHUCK: Oh! Like everybody else?

REIN: Like everybody else.

CHUCK: Except us. Alright, well do you want to introduce yourself really quick? And then we’ll get into our topic.

REIN: Sure! My name is Rein Henrichs. I am a Ruby developer and web developer. I’m a distributed systems builder. I’m somewhat of a security nuts, mostly because I got hacked a couple of years ago and that really sucks. And so I’ve been doing my best to make sure that doesn’t happen to me or other people ever since.

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>59:45</itunes:duration>
	</item>