<item>
		<title>050 RR Hungry Academy with Jeff Casimir</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/050-rr-hungry-academy-with-jeff-casimir/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/050-rr-hungry-academy-with-jeff-casimir/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 07:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Casimir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=502</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Jeff Casimir (Jumpstart Lab Hungry Academy) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp) James Edward Gray (blog twitter github) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Discussion Steve Klabnik Experts frequently forget the novice perspective Pragmatic Thinking and Learning the Dreyfus Model Teaching is a skill Teaching is about empathy &#8220;Why don&#8217;t you move your legs faster?!&#8221; Open yourself [...]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/050-rr-hungry-academy-with-jeff-casimir/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR50HungryAcademy.mp3" length="73885478" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Jeff Casimir (Jumpstart Lab Hungry Academy)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp)   James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog) - Discus...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Jeff Casimir (Jumpstart Lab Hungry Academy)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp)
	James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)

Discussion

	Steve Klabnik
	Experts frequently forget the novice perspective
	Pragmatic Thinking and Learning
	the Dreyfus Model
	Teaching is a skill
	Teaching is about empathy
	"Why don't you move your legs faster?!"
	Open yourself up to Feedback
	Live teaching can (to a certain extent) never be replaced
	A book cannot anticipate every learning direction
	Jumpstart Lab
	Hungry Academy
	You can teach someone everything they'd learn in a decent Computer Science program in 6 months.
	Computer Science should prepare you for what you'll specialize in when you get out into the workforce.
	Assembler
	Pareto's Principle
	Matt Yoho
	CodeNow
	Hungry Academy application process
	LSAT
	How do people respond to coaching?
	The class started March 6
	They're not working on commercial projects.
	Students get paid to be at Hungry Academy
	16 of 24 were identified as non-developers
	6 of 24 have a traditional Computer Science background
	Be deliberate about how you structure your teams
	The country is transitioning to an information economy
	What does it take to get people from the low income areas to something like Hungry Academy?
	We need an ignition for minorities to get into programming
	Maslow's Hierarchy
	RailsBridge
	A small group over a long time rather than a large group over a short time.
	LAYC
	LivingSocial
	CodeAcademy
	HackerSchool
	DevBootcamp
	Ruby
	Ruby on Rails
	Donors Choose
	BigData
	iPad
	Javascript frontends
	What are the prerequisites for Hungry Academy?

	You have to have drive


	Diversity
	DRb

Picks

	The Rails View (Jeff)
	Rails Recipes 3rd edition (James)
	Tmux book (James)
	Deploying with JRuby - Beta (James)
	ZeFrank (Josh)
	Dr Nic's Scrolls (Josh)
	Therapeutic Massage (Josh)
	Parallels Workstation (Avdi)
	Air Deflector (Chuck)
	Shock Mount (Chuck)
	guard (Chuck)
	Coast (Chuck)
	Meteor (Jeff)

Transcript 
CHUCK: Does it involve lightning and a brain transplant?

*laughter*

JAMES: Yes!

JOSH: No. But it does involve a fight ***.



CHUCK: [This podcast is sponsored by New Relic.  To track and optimize your application’s performance, to go rubygogues.com/newrelic]

[This podcast is also sponsored by railsthemes.com. Have an app your mother could love? Check our railstheme.com. They’re also giving out some pretty cool swag at RailsConf. So find them, get some and thank them for sponsoring Ruby Rogues.]

Hey everybody and welcome Episode 50 of the Ruby Rogue podcast. That’s right, we’ve done 50 of this. This week on our panel, we have Avdi Grimm.

AVDI: Hello, hello.

CHUCK: We also have James Edward Gray.

JAMES: Hey everybody.

CHUCK: Josh Susser.

JOSH: Good morning.

CHUCK: And I’m Charles Max Wood from teachmethecode.com. We also have a guest Rogue, that’s Jeff Casimir.

JEFF: Hello.

CHUCK: Jeff do you want to introduce yourself really quickly for the people who don’t know who you are?

JEFF: Sure, my name is Jeff Casimir. I’m from DC. Right now I‘m the lead instructor of Hungry Academy. I also run a small training company called Jumpstart Lab. Run around the word teaching Ruby on Rails classes.

CHUCK: Cool.

JAMES: You don’t take a plane?

JEFF: Ah you know, occasionally, but you got to stay in shape so.

CHUCK: I was talking to Steve Klabnik who’s also been on the show incidentally and I didn’t know that he is working for you so...

JEFF: Yeah, Steve is working on teaching specially, co-teaching some of the larger classes, so it’s really nice to have two teachers in the room. Get a little bit more of a dialogue. Also, I love that Steve knows a lot more than I do about pretty much everything.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:01:34</itunes:duration>
	</item>