<item>
		<title>114 RR Elixir with José Valim</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/114-rr-elixir-with-jose-valim/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/114-rr-elixir-with-jose-valim/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 12:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jose Valim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1407</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel José Valim (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:08 &#8211; José Valim Introduction 048 RR Crafting [...]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/114-rr-elixir-with-jose-valim/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR114Elixir.mp3" length="65498565" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  José Valim (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	José Valim (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:08 - José Valim Introduction

	048 RR Crafting Rails Applications with José Valim

02:37 - Elixir


	Functional Programming Language
	Erlang
	Seven Languages in Seven Weeks: A Pragmatic Guide to Learning Programming Languages by Bruce A. Tate

07:00 - Elixir and Happiness
08:50 - Naming Elixir


	WORDOID

09:55- The Erlang Virtual Machine


	Introduction to Elixir: a New Language on the VM - José Valim
	Routing
	Aaron Patterson: Pattern Matching and Rails Routes at MagRails
	Aaron's Routing Code

17:20 - Functional Programming with a Ruby Style Syntax


	Additional Parenthesis
	Metaprogramming &amp; Macros
	LISP
	Lambdas

25:25 - Language Design


	Riak
	Bang

39:30 - Elixir Moving to Web?


	AMNESIA

41:20 - “Everything in Elixir is an Expression”


	The Return Method of Modules

48:25 - The Actor Model &amp; Elixir
54:23 - Resources


	Erlang
	ferd.ca -&gt; An Open Letter to the Erlang Beginner (or Onlooker)
	Programming Elixir by Dave Thomas
	Programming Erlang: Software for Concurrent World by Joe Armstrong
	Meet Elixir | PeepCode Screencasts
	The Erlangelist

Picks

	Meet Elixir | PeepCode Screencasts (Avdi)
	Wilfred (Avdi)
	Erlang: The Movie (Katrina)
	Bryan Helmkamp’s Security Email Course (Katrina)
	David Brady (David)
	My Emacs Setup, pt 1 | polishing ruby by ryan davis (James)
	Star Trek: Enterprise (James)
	pessimize (Josh)
	Using the pessimistic version constraint operator with ruby gem versions | Jon Cairns (Josh)
	@YiddishProverbs (Josh)
	Alias (Chuck)
	Under the Dome (Chuck)
	benjamin.tan: Elixir for the Lazy Impatient and Busy: Part 3 I&gt; Processes 102 (José)
	Unerdwear: Underwear for Nerds (José)
	Todd and the Book of Pure Evil (José)

Book Club
Understanding Computation: From Simple Machines to Impossible Programs by Tom Stuart!  He will join us for an episode to discuss the book on August 14th. The episode will air on August 21st. O’Reilly has generously offered our listeners a discount code. Use the code RUBYROGUES to receive 50% off the eBook and 40% off the print version. *Discount does not apply to the ebook + print bundle.
Next Week
Functional and Object-Oriented Programming with Jessica Kerr
Transcript
CHUCK:  I’m so tired I could use a wake-up Elixir.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at Bluebox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

 [This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built-in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to JetBrains.com/Ruby.] 

CHUCK:  Hey everybody, and welcome to Episode 114 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Good morning, everyone.

CHUCK:  Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Witty greeting.

CHUCK:  Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello.

CHUCK:  David Brady.

DAVID:  Currently not seeking asylum in Russia. This is David Brady.

CHUCK:  Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Hello.

CHUCK:  And I'm Charles Max Wood from DevChat.TV. This week, we have a special guest and that’s Jose Valim.

JOSE:  Hello.

CHUCK:  We haven’t had you on the show for a while, Jose.

JOSE:  Yes, what was the last time? A year ago, two years ago?

JAMES:  Yes, it was a while ago.

CHUCK:  It was about a year or so ago, we read your book.

DAVID:  We heard you hate Ruby now.

[Laughter]

JOSE:  That’s not true.

JAMES:  That’s why we didn’t bring him back, he switched sides.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:08:14</itunes:duration>
	</item>