<item>
		<title>119 RR Accessibility with Brian Hogan</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/119-rr-accessibility-with-brian-hogan/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/119-rr-accessibility-with-brian-hogan/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brian Hogan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1466</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Brian Hogan (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:39 &#8211; Brian Hogan Introduction tmux: Productive Mouse-Free Development by Brian Hogan HTML5 [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/119-rr-accessibility-with-brian-hogan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR119Accessibility.mp3" length="74299920" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Brian Hogan (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog) </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Brian Hogan (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:39 - Brian Hogan Introduction

	tmux: Productive Mouse-Free Development by Brian Hogan
	HTML5 and CSS3: Develop with Tomorrow’s Standards Today by Brian Hogan
	Web Development Recipes by Brian P. Hogan, Chris Warren, Mike Weber, Chris Johnson, Aaron Godin
	Development Editor with Pragmatic Bookshelf
	Professor at Chippewa Valley Technical College

02:09 - What Accessibility Means
06:50 - Making Things Accessible


	Transcripts
	Video Scripts &amp; Captions

08:35 - Is There a Downside to Making Things Accessible?


	Disabling JavaScript

11:28 - ARIA Roles


	ARIA – HTML5
	WAI-ARIA Live Regions and HTML5

15:19 - Keyboard Shortcuts
17:50 - Assistive Technologies
24:25 - Accessibility Awareness


	058 JSJ Building Accessible Website with Brian Hogan
	Sympathy vs Empathy
	Pixels vs Relative

29:16 - Tools


	W3C Markup Validation Service
	WebAIM - Web Accessibility In Mind
	WebAIM's WCAG 2.0 Checklist for HTML documents
	Color Oracle
	JAWS

35:04 - Web Innovation and Accessibility


	Infinite Scroll
	URL Changing

39:26 - Backend Technologies
41:42 - Internationalization &amp; ESL
45:29 - Accessibility for People with Cognitive Impairment
47:38 - Hearing Impairment
48:30 - Documentation
50:07 - Accessibility in Apps
53:45 - Accessibility Audits
54:57 - Framework Improvements
59:35 - Accessible Websites


	Google Maps
	Twitter

01:01:16 - Resources


	WebAIM - Web Accessibility In Mind
	webaxe Podcast
	HTML5 accessibility

Picks

	Strategic IT Accessibility: Enabling the Organization by Jeff Kline (David)
	egghead.io (David)
	A Wizard of Earthsea by Ursula Le Guin (Josh)
	True Names by Vernor Vinge (Josh)
	Kathy Sierra's Blog -- Serious Pony (James)
	@seriouspony (James)
	Ruby Warrior (Avdi)
	Object Playground: The Definitive Guide to Object-Oriented JavaScript (Avdi)
	APL Demonstration from 1975 (Avdi)
	ng-conf (Chuck)
	Ember 101 Screencasts (Chuck)
	Wistia (Chuck)
	HTML5 and CSS3 (2nd edition): Level Up with Today's Web Technologies by Brian P. Hogan (Brian)
	Pro HTML5 Accessibility by Joshue O Connor (Brian)
	Beat Hazard (Brian)

Next Week
Book Club: Understanding Computation with Tom Stuart
Transcript
CHUCK:  I had a weird dream last night, Avdi, that you were marketing hair care products along with your Ruby Tapas.

[Chuckles]

AVDI:  Interesting.

JAMES:  That’s a brilliant idea, actually. “Take in some confident code and while you’re at it, this nice shampoo and conditioner package.”



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built-in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to JetBrains.com/Ruby.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.]

[This episode is sponsored by Code Climate. Over one thousand organizations trust Code Climate to help improve quality and security in their Ruby apps. Get 50% off your first three months for being a Rogues listener by starting a free trial this week. Go to RubyRogues.com/CodeClimate.]

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to episode 119 of the Ruby Rogues Podcast. This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  I’ve stopped listening to the new civil wars album long enough to record this episode.

CHUCK:  Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello.

CHUCK:  David Brady. [Silence]

Josh Susser.

JOSH:  I think David’s off solving The Halting Problem. He’ll be right back.

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:17:24</itunes:duration>
	</item>