<item>
		<title>121 RR Consulting vs Product Work with Adam Keys</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/121-rr-consulting-vs-product-work-with-adam-keys/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/121-rr-consulting-vs-product-work-with-adam-keys/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Adam Keys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1490</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Adam Keys (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:17 &#8211; Adam Keys Introduction Keeping Up with Gowalla with Adam Keys LivingSocial Sifter [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/121-rr-consulting-vs-product-work-with-adam-keys/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR121ProductVsConsulting.mp3" length="73893674" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Adam Keys (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rai...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Adam Keys (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:17 - Adam Keys Introduction

	Keeping Up with Gowalla with Adam Keys
	LivingSocial
	Sifter

02:11 - What is a Consultant?
03:58 - Consultants vs Contractors
04:46 - Consulting Work vs Product Work


	Perspective &amp; Goals
	Cash Flow

08:39 - Making the Product Better vs Getting Paid
13:15 - Good Consultants vs Bad Consultants
15:11 - Freedom of Experimentation


	Communication

18:16 - Responsibility for writing good code
20:38 - Are consultants more likely to speak at conferences or work on things like podcasts?


	Permission to take time off
	Billable Hours

26:26 - Development Process: Freelance vs Full Time
31:02 - Attitude Towards Writing Code


	Cutthroat vs Quality Code

37:56 - Job Security


	The Prisoner’s Dilemma

41:42 - Technology Choices


	Risk

45:07 - Iteration vs Long-Term Thinking, Architecture &amp; Design
55:16 - Grinders, Cowboy Coders, and Cut Rate Consultants

Picks

	pbrisbin - chruby (James)
	chruby (James)
	ruby-install (James)
	ASUS RT-N66u (Avdi)
	WhatTheFont (Avdi)
	Ruby Ramen (Avdi)
	The Game of Life in 140 Characters (Josh)
	Socrates Jones: Pro Philosopher (Josh)
	The Best Map Ever Made of America’s Racial Segregation (Josh)
	David Brady: Loyalty and Layoffs (Chuck)
	Sports and Pop Culture (Adam)

Book Club
Confident Ruby by Avdi Grimm! Use the discount code ROGUESCLUB for 20% off of any of the editions! Avdi will talk about the book on the show on October 16th, 2013.
Next Week
Daemons with Kenneth Kalmer
Transcript
JOSH:  How is your tattoo feeling there, James?

JAMES:  It kind of hurts. Thanks!

[Laughter]

[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built-in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to JetBrains.com/Ruby.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.]

[This episode is sponsored by Code Climate. Code Climates’ new security monitor alerts you immediately when vulnerabilities are introduced into your Rails app. Sleep better knowing that your data is protected. Try it free at RubyRogues.com/CodeClimate.]

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to episode 121 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello!

CHUCK:  Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Good morning.

CHUCK:  Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Hello.

CHUCK:  James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Good morning.

CHUCK:  I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.TV. And this week, we have a special guest, Adam Keys.

ADAM:  Hello there.

CHUCK:  You’ve been on the show before, Adam. Do you want to introduce your self anyway?

ADAM:  Sure. I'm Adam, I'm from Texas. I currently work at LivingSocial and work on Sifter app on the side. I've only been a consultant for like four months of my life. So, there.

CHUCK:  [Laughs] Is that a good thing or a bad thing?

ADAM:  It was a discovery process. I learned that I liked just working on a product more than doing all the other things that consulting work entails.

JAMES:  That’s kind of funny actually. I was wondering if you were going to say it was the worst four months of your life. But for me, I think it’s almost backwards, like I love the constantly seeing new things and stuff like that. So, I never feel like I'm bored and stuff.

JOSH:  Hey, maybe we can start with a definition. Like, what is a consultant?

JAMES:  What is a consultant? Yes.

JOSH:  What do you mean by ‘consultant’?</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:16:58</itunes:duration>
	</item>