<item>
		<title>122 RR Daemons with Kenneth Kalmer</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/122-rr-daemons-with-kenneth-kalmer/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/122-rr-daemons-with-kenneth-kalmer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 12:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kenneth Kalmer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1496</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Kenneth Kalmer (twitter github blog ValuationUP) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:49 &#8211; Kenneth Kalmer Introduction 02:33 &#8211; How to say “daemon” 03:47 &#8211; [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/122-rr-daemons-with-kenneth-kalmer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR122Daemons.mp3" length="69639254" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Kenneth Kalmer (twitter github blog ValuationUP)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Kenneth Kalmer (twitter github blog ValuationUP)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:49 - Kenneth Kalmer Introduction
02:33 - How to say “daemon”
03:47 - Definition


	Tammer Saleh: Angels and Daemons

04:48 - Sending signals to daemons
06:02 - What daemons are used for


	daemon-kit

08:26 - The process of starting up a daemon


	ruby/ruby/blob/trunk/lib/webrick/server.rb#L45

11:10 - .pid file management
13:40 - Cron Job


	058 RR Book Club: Working with Unix Processes with Jesse Storimer

17:37 - Why the JVM isn’t good for running daemons


	god
	bluepill

20:18 - Daemonizing on a Windows system


	Win32Utils - Ruby Libraries for MS Windows
	win32-service

21:53 - Getting daemons to start up when the server starts


	god
	foreman
	monit

25:02 - Writing a daemon


	rufus-scheduler

29:22 - When would you want to create your own daemon?


	Metrics Gathering

32:54 - Communicating with daemons


	blather
	AMQP
	mkfifo

36:29 - Deployment cycle for daemons


	capistrano

40:11 - Sharing Code


	SIGTERM VS. SIGKILL

48:51 - What do you put in the payload of the jobs?


	Unicorn!

53:23 - Knowing when something goes wrong


	Exceptional Ruby by Avdi Grimm
	zero-zero
	safely

Picks

	servolux (Katrina)
	Aral Balkan: Superheroes &amp; Villains in Design (Katrina)
	A Unix Utility You Should Know About: Pipe Viewer (Josh)
	Pipe Viewer: Online Man Page (Josh)
	The Mote in God's Eye by Larry Niven (Josh)
	James' Google+ Hangout: Emacs Part 1 (James)
	James' Google+ Hangout: Emacs Part 2 (James)
	James Edward Gray: Ruby 2 Jeopardy (James)
	Dungeons of Dredmor (James)
	Prince (Avdi)
	DocRaptor (Avdi)
	XMLStarlet Command Line XML Toolkit (Avdi)
	Evernote (Chuck)
	The MacSparky Paperless Field Guide by David Sparks  (Chuck)
	Fujisu ScanSnap S1300i (Chuck)
	SaneBox (Chuck)
	Gmail (Chuck)
	Tammer Saleh: Angels and Daemons (Kenneth)
	Rubyfuza (Kenneth)
	Oppikoppi (Kenneth)
	Manna: the beer drone at Oppikoppi (Kenneth)
	99% Invisible (Kenneth)
	Radiolab (Kenneth)

Book Club
Confident Ruby by Avdi Grimm! Use the discount code ROGUESCLUB for 20% off of any of the editions! Avdi will talk about the book on the show on October 16th, 2013.
Next Week
ROM with Piotr Solnica
Transcript
KATRINA:  Can you say, “I believe I broke his jaw”?

KENNETH:  Who, me?

KATRINA:  Yes, you. Of course, you.

KENNETH:  I believe I broke his jaw.

KATRINA:  Ah! It’s so brilliant.

JAMES:  Okay, now you have to explain that.

[Laughter]

KATRINA:  I think at the first Mission Impossible movie, there are some really bad guys from South Africa and one of them says, “I believe I broke his jaw,” and it’s so funny.

[Laughter]

CHUCK:  Okay.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built-in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to JetBrains.com/Ruby.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.]

[This episode is sponsored by Code Climate. Code Climate automated code reviews ensure that your projects stay on track. Fix and find quality and security issues in your Ruby code sooner. Try it free at RubyRogues.com/CodeClimate.]

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to episode 122 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Good morning everyone.

CHUCK:  Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Everything done for the first time unleashes a daemon.

CHUCK:  Katrina Owen.

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:12:32</itunes:duration>
	</item>