<item>
		<title>126 RR Remote Pair Programming with Sam Livingston-Gray</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/126-rr-remote-pair-programming-with-sam-livingston-gray/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/126-rr-remote-pair-programming-with-sam-livingston-gray/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Livingston-Gray]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1527</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Sam Livingston-Gray (twitter github blog) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:50 &#8211; Sam Livingston-Gray Introduction LivingSocial 02:52 &#8211; Remote Pairing 04:41 &#8211; Tools GNU [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/126-rr-remote-pair-programming-with-sam-livingston-gray/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR126RemotePairing.mp3" length="66563931" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Sam Livingston-Gray (twitter github blog)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Sam Livingston-Gray (twitter github blog)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:50 - Sam Livingston-Gray Introduction

	LivingSocial

02:52 - Remote Pairing
04:41 - Tools


	GNU Screen
	tmux
	Cloud9 IDE
	Floobits
	Google Drive
	OmniGraffle
	Screenhero
	Skype

13:35 - Terminal Configuration/Setup


	Vim vs Emacs
	ls-pair
	Pair Program with Me
	dbrady/emacs_libs
	PeepCode: Commanding Your Text Editor

27:24 - Face-to-Face Interaction &amp; Telepresence


	Pivotal Labs: Pairing tete-a-tete
	Teleport

42:51 - Pairing, Remote Work and LivingSocial
44:51 - Conquering Pairing Intimidation


	exercism.io

51:43 - Recording Pair Programming Sessions


	Josh and Avdi Pairing on Discourse
	Play by Play | PeepCode Screencasts

53:47 - Tom Howlett: The Shame of Pair Programming
54:31 - Advice for Pair Programmers


	Get your ego in check
	Good hygiene
	Good Connection
	Use a Headset
	Keyboard Noise
	ls-pair/README

Picks

	Editor Wars: Revenge of the... oh, whatever. (David)
	PSY vs LMFAO - Sexy Style (Mash-up) (David)
	Katy Perry vs. Green Day vs Coldplay - Wide Awake on Paradise Boulevard (Mash-up) (David)
	JavaScript: The Definitive Guide: Activate Your Web Pages by David Flanagan (James)
	Every Day: A Five-Year Memory Book by Mr. Boddington's Studio (James)
	Joe Moore: Remote Pair Programming (Josh)
	AllTheBadges.io (Katrina)
	Terrafab (Katrina)
	Every Time Zone (Chuck)
	Parallels (Chuck)
	GoToMeeting (Chuck)
	Evernote (Chuck)
	Bacon Biz (Chuck)
	Ada Developers Academy (Sam)
	IndieGoGo campaign for Ada Developers Academy (Sam)
	Find or make a community you can learn with and learn from (Sam)
	Calagator (and source is at calagator) (Sam)
	Ruby Hangman 2013-02-05 (Sam)

Book Club
Confident Ruby by Avdi Grimm! Use the discount code ROGUESCLUB for 20% off of any of the editions! Avdi will talk about the book on the show on October 16th, 2013.
Next Week
Erik Michaels-Ober
Transcript
DAVID:  Probably the biggest perk of working for the NSA is that you get the Ruby Rogues episodes a week before they air.

[Laughter]



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.]

[This episode is sponsored by Code Climate. Code Climate’s new security monitor alerts you immediately when vulnerabilities are introduced into your Rails app. Sleep better knowing that your data is protected. Try it free at RubyRogues.com/CodeClimate.]

[This episode is sponsored by SendGrid, the leader in transactional email and email deliverability. SendGrid helps eliminate the cost and complexity of owning and maintaining your own email infrastructure by handling ISP monitoring, DKIM, SPF, feedback loops, whitelabeling, link customization and more. If you’d rather focus on your business than on scaling your email infrastructure, then visit www.SendGrid.com.]

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to episode 126 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have Josh Susser.

JOSH:  I will not be making any jokes today.

CHUCK:  James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  We do the government shutdown, we’re all doing this podcast without a paycheck.

CHUCK:  Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  I don’t make jokes anywhere or anytime.

CHUCK:  David Brady.

DAVID:  [keyboard typing] I've just got to get this last piece of code to compile and…go!

CHUCK:  I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.TV. I just want to remind you to go check out my freelancing video at GoingRogueVideo.com. We also have a special guest and that is Sam Livingston-Gray.

SAM:  Hello from the sunny Portland, Oregon.

JAMES:  Woohoo!

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:09:20</itunes:duration>
	</item>