<item>
		<title>129 RR Sharpening Tools with Ben Orenstein</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/129-rr-sharpening-tools-with-ben-orenstein/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/129-rr-sharpening-tools-with-ben-orenstein/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 13:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Max Wood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben Orenstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1553</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Ben Orenstein (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:29 &#8211; Ben Orenstein Introduction Giant Robots Smashing into other Giant Robots thoughtbot thoughtbot [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/129-rr-sharpening-tools-with-ben-orenstein/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR129SharpeningTools.mp3" length="60416992" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Ben Orenstein (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Ben Orenstein (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:29 - Ben Orenstein Introduction


	Giant Robots Smashing into other Giant Robots
	thoughtbot
	thoughtbot Learn

04:23 - Tool Sharpening


	Play by Play: Refactoring with Ben Orenstein
	Ben's GoGaRuCo Talk

07:16 - Coding Environment


	Remaps and Shortcuts
	Learning New Commands
	Disabling Commands

20:06 - Prioritizing Things
21:08 - Tool Sharpening Activities
22:55 - Sharpening Skills
26:26 - Tool Sharpening with Teams and Organizations


	Changing Policies and Procedures
	Big vs Small Company Resistance
	Making Improvements

35:52 - Operating System Sharpening


	Alfred App
	SizeUp
	Vimium
	LaunchBar

39:32 - Hardware &amp; Other Physical Tools


	Kinesis Advantage Ergonomic Keyboard
	GeekDesk
	A standing desk for $22
	VIVOBAREFOOT
	Ruby Rogues Episode 074: Developer Environments

48:37 - Favorite Remap


	Dash

53:33 - Upcoming Appearances


	RubyConf
	Garden City Ruby

Picks

	oj (James)
	I introduced my 5-year-old and 2-year-old to startx and xmonad. They’re DELIGHTED! (James)
	Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs (James)
	thoughtbot Learn (Avdi)
	Hybrid Kangaroo (Avdi)
	There's Plenty of Room at the Bottom by Richard P. Feynman (Josh)
	MS Fnd in a Lbry (Josh)
	The Secret Weapon (Chuck)
	Narcissistic Design - Stuart Halloway (Ben)

Book Club
Functional Programming for the Object-Oriented Programmer by Brian Marick! We will be interviewing Brian on December 18th, and the show will air on Christmas Day. Oh! And here's a $5.00 off code to get the book: please_remember_the_starving_artist

So, well, Merry Christmas!
Next Week
Data Visualization with Aja Hammerly
Transcript
BEN:  I’ll take heckling over like lack of audience attention any day.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.]

[This episode is sponsored by Code Climate. Raise the visibility of quality within your team with Code Climate and start shipping better code faster. Try it free at RubyRogues.com/CodeClimate.]

[This episode is sponsored by SendGrid, the leader in transactional email and email deliverability. SendGrid helps eliminate the cost and complexity of owning and maintaining your own email infrastructure by handling ISP monitoring, DKIM, SPF, feedback loops, whitelabeling, link customization and more. If you’d rather focus on your business than on scaling your email infrastructure, then visit www.SendGrid.com.]

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to episode 129 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Good morning, everyone.

CHUCK:  Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Good morning from San Francisco where the visibility is about 50 feet.

CHUCK:  Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Good morning from Pennsylvania.

CHUCK:  Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Good morning from Denver.

CHUCK:  I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.TV. And this week, we have a special guest and that is Ben Orenstein.

BEN:  Hello from thoughtbot in Boston.

CHUCK:  So Ben, you’re the host of a fairly popular podcast.

JAMES:  Wait! Don’t say that on our show.

[Laughter]

JOSH:  Competition, man.

BEN:  From a tiny little, barely relevant podcast.

JAMES:  [Laughs]

CHUCK:  Yeah, it’s the same name as the blog, right? Giant Robots Smashing into other Giant Robots?

BEN:  It is. That’s right. We only have the ability to come up with one good name after a few years.

JOSH:  Chuck, you have to say it with the voice.

AVDI:  Yeah, you have to say, ‘Giant Robots’.

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:02:56</itunes:duration>
	</item>