<item>
		<title>149 RR Ruby in Government with Sarah Allen</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/149-rr-ruby-in-government-with-sarah-allen/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/149-rr-ruby-in-government-with-sarah-allen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Allen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1780</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Sarah Allen (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Discussion 01:44 &#8211; Ruby Best Practice Patterns Project is Cancelled 02:47 &#8211; Sarah Allen Introduction Bridge Foundry RailsBridge Presidential Innovation Fellows 04:16 &#8211; Sarah Allen: Why no ruby in gov? (Slideshare) 08:25 [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/149-rr-ruby-in-government-with-sarah-allen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR149RubyInGovernment.mp3" length="70907678" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Sarah Allen (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) - Discussion 01:44 - Ruby Best Practice Patterns Project is Cancelled </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Sarah Allen (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)

Discussion
01:44 - Ruby Best Practice Patterns Project is Cancelled
02:47 - Sarah Allen Introduction


	Bridge Foundry
	RailsBridge
	Presidential Innovation Fellows

04:16 - Sarah Allen: Why no ruby in gov? (Slideshare)
08:25 - Government, Ruby, and Agile Development
14:04 - The Smithsonian Environment, Coding Processes, &amp; CMS


	Drupal
	PHP
	transcription.si.edu
	WordPress
	Joomla!
	Radiant CMS
	The Ruby Toolbox

41:43 - Working with Government


	18F Digital Services Delivery
	Open Data within Government

56:34 - Day to Day Experience Working at the Smithsonian &amp; Smithsonian History
01:03:17 - Getting Involved


	Presidential Innovation Fellows
	Sarah Allen: Why no ruby in gov? (Slideshare)

Picks

	moto x (Avdi)
	Ruby Hero Awards (Josh)
	Martin Fowler: Microservices (James)
	The Tectonic Podcast (Sarah)
	Luce Foundation Center for American Art - Hackathon (Sarah)
	Screenhero (Sarah)

Book Club
Object Design: Roles, Responsibilities, and Collaborations by Rebecca Wirfs-Brock and Alan McKean
Next Week
The Debugging Mindset with Danielle Sucher
Transcript
JAMES:  Alright, are we ready? Are we buckled up?

JOSH:  Oh, wait. Yes.

[Chuckles]

JOSH:  I will not fall out of my chair this morning.

JAMES:  Good. I would hate to have that happen on the air.

JOSH:  Again.

JAMES:  Again, right.

JOSH:  [Laughs]

JAMES:  It had happened before. I’m just saying. It was Josh, just to be clear.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.]

[Does your application need to send emails? Did you know that 20% of all email doesn’t even get delivered to the inbox? SendGrid can help you get your message delivered every time. Go to RubyRogues.com/SendGrid, sign up for free and tell them thanks.]

[Bandwidth for this segment is provided by CacheFly, the world’s fastest CDN. Deliver your content fast with CacheFly. Visit CacheFly.com to learn more.]

JAMES:  Hello everyone and welcome to episode 149 of the Ruby Rogues Podcast. I’m James Gray and I’ll be your host since Chuck is out today. With me as always is Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Good morning, afternoon, something.

JAMES:  Josh Susser.

JOSH:  Good day from sunny San Francisco.

JAMES:  And today, we also have a special guest, Sarah Allen.

SARAH:  Hello, also from sunny San Francisco.

JOSH:  Hey, neighbor!

SARAH:  Hi.

JAMES:  Usually, we have multiple people from Utah. Today, it’s multiple people from California, I guess.

JOSH:  Yeah, yeah. So hey, thanks for joining us on the show, Sarah.

JAMES:  Yes.

SARAH:  It’s really great to be here.

JAMES:  Absolutely. I’m going to have you introduce yourself in just a second Sarah, because we’ll get into what you do and stuff as we start to talk. Before we do that though, we do have an announcement.

We’ve covered this on Parley, but we haven’t mentioned it on the air before. We talked in the past about doing a Ruby Best Practice Patterns Project. And we’ve actually been working on that for a while and trying to get a contract settled with the publisher and things like that. Unfortunately that project has not worked out. And we’ve decided to abandon it, because it was chewing time and resources trying to set it up and we were not finding something that everyone was comfortable with. But that’s okay. We’re doing other projects and interesting things. I just did the first Ruby quiz study group on a Google Hangout. And we recorded that and did all that. We have more experiments coming. So, it’s a little sad that the project’s ending. But we’re redirecting that energy to other places.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:13:52</itunes:duration>
	</item>