<item>
		<title>154 RR Indie Game Development with Megan Fox</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/154-rr-indie-game-development-with-megan-fox/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/154-rr-indie-game-development-with-megan-fox/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Megan Fox]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1835</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Megan Fox (twitter blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:35 &#8211; Megan Fox Introduction Glass Bottom Games Jones On Fire [Kickstarter] Hot Tin Roof 02:16 &#8211; Making Games [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/154-rr-indie-game-development-with-megan-fox/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR154GameDev.mp3" length="65032936" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Megan Fox (twitter blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) - Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Megan Fox (twitter blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:35 - Megan Fox Introduction


	Glass Bottom Games
	Jones On Fire
	[Kickstarter] Hot Tin Roof

02:16 - Making Games


	Unity
	Unreal Engine
	Roguelike
	Photoshop

06:43 - Finding an Artist


	The Something Awful Forums
	Ludem Dare
	Polycount Forum
	Twitter
	OpenGameArt
	3ds Max
	Maya
	FRACT OSC

11:31 - The Indie Game Space &amp; the Indie Game Movement


	Unreal Engine
	Sean Hollister: Epic drastically drops the price of Unreal Engine game development
	ShaderLab
	CryENGINE
	The golden age of indie gaming has arrived
	The DIY Wave of Indie Gaming
	Alec Holowka (@infinite_ammo)
	Aquaria
	World of Goo
	Steam
	TowerFall
	Shahid Kamal Ahmad (@shahidkamal)
	Chris Charla (@iocat)
	Pub Fund

29:40 - Steam Machines
31:59 - Mobile Games vs Console/PC Games
35:03 - The Gaming Community


	Ludum Dare
	Amnesia Fortnight
	7DRL
	7DFPS

40:32 - The Gamers and The Writers


	Juice It or Lose It Video
	Beat Hazard

47:46 - Getting Started in Gaming


	MMO
	Disco Zoo
	Vungle

Picks

	Michael Fairley: Rapid Game Prototyping with Ruby (James)
	Mike Moore: Writing Games with Ruby (James)
	[Amazon] HTML5 Games (James)
	[Amazon] JavaScript Game Programming (James)
	[Amazon] Kid Game Programming (James)
	DartGameDevs (James)
	ThinkPad Compact USB Keyboard With TrackPoint (Avdi)
	The Great Smoky Mountains (Avdi)
	Gatlinburg (Avdi)
	Your Local Science Center (Avdi)
	The Whitaker Center (Avdi)
	[The Ruby Toolbox] Game Libraries (David)
	Gosu (David)
	Chipmunk (David)
	releasy (David)
	Half-Life (David)
	Half-Life 2 (David)
	Diablo III (Chuck)
	Multiwinia (Chuck)
	The iPhreaks Show #47 – Game Development with Giant Spacekat of Revolution 60 with Brianna Wu, Amanda Stenquist Warner, and Maria Enderton (Chuck)
	Hatching Twitter: A True Story of Money, Power, Friendship, and Betrayal by Nick Bilton (Chuck)
	The Total Money Makeover: A Proven Plan for Financial Fitness by Dave Ramsey (Chuck)
	Platform: Get Noticed in a Noisy World by Michael Hyatt (Chuck)
	HabitRPG (Chuck)
	Unreal Engine 4 (Megan)
	Unity (Megan)
	Scratch (Megan)
	National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) (Megan)
	FRACT OSC (Megan)
	SkyRim (Megan)
	#onegameamonth by @McFunkypants (Megan)

Book Club
Object Design: Roles, Responsibilities, and Collaborations by Rebecca Wirfs-Brock and Alan McKean
Next Week
Why Ruby Sucks
Transcript
CHUCK:  Isn’t there a celebrity named Megan Fox?

MEGAN:  There is. But I’m the cool one.

DAVID:  I loved you in Transformers, by the way.

MEGAN:  Oh, thank you.

[Laughter]

MEGAN:  It was some of my best work.



[This episode is sponsored by Rackspace. Are you looking for a place to host your latest creation? Want terrific support, high performance all backed by the largest open source cloud? What if you could try it for free? Try out Rackspace at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace and get a $300 credit over six months. That’s $50 per month at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace.]

[DevMynd is a software design and development studio in Chicago with expertise in Ruby, JavaScript, and Clojure. We believe that well-crafted software makes life better. And our team of designers and engineers is dedicated to that pursuit. We love our customers, we love our team, and we spend a lot of time and effort making sure that we fit the right projects with the right people. Get in touch at DevMynd.com.]

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.]

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to episode 154 of the Ruby Rogues Podcast. This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Hello from JavaScript Jabber.

CHUCK:  Avdi Grimm.

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:07:45</itunes:duration>
	</item>