<item>
		<title>161 RR Docker Deploys with Sam Saffron</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/161-rr-docker-deploys-with-sam-saffron/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/161-rr-docker-deploys-with-sam-saffron/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 14:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Saffron]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1890</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Sam Saffron (twitter blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 02:04 &#8211; Sam Saffron Discourse Ruby Rogues Episode #117:Discourse Part 2 with Sam Saffron and Robin Ward Stack Overflow [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/161-rr-docker-deploys-with-sam-saffron/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR161DockerDeploys.mp3" length="69521393" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Sam Saffron (twitter blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) - Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Sam Saffron (twitter blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
02:04 - Sam Saffron

	Discourse
	Ruby Rogues Episode #117:Discourse Part 2 with Sam Saffron and Robin Ward
	Stack Overflow

03:55 - Deploying Discourse


	discourse_docker
	nginx
	paravirtualization

13:19 - Layering File System
15:19 - The Docker Setup for Discourse


	docker_container
	pups
	runit

	Process Supervision: Solved Problem


	bluepill
	God
	Monit

25:04 - Instructions
31:50 - Managing Containers
32:47 - Updates


	unicorn
	passenger-docker

36:34 - logster


	logster

37:36 - Docker and Vagrant


	vagrant-lxc
	Docker Provisioner
	Chef

41:33 - Getting Started
45:32 - Storing Images
47:25 - Containers (Cont’d)


	CoreOS
	OpenStack
	logstash
	Elasticsearch
	dawn
	HAProxy

58:46 - Deploying Containers


	Jenkins CI
	DigitalOcean
	boot2docker
	Idris

01:01:23 - Memory
Picks

	Xiki: The Command Revolution (James)
	Xero (Avdi)
	Class: CSV (Ruby 2.1.0) (Avdi)
	Runtastic (Avdi)
	Try Docker (Chuck)
	The Miracle Morning: The Not-So-Obvious Secret Guaranteed to Transform Your Life (Before 8AM) by Hal Elrod (Chuck)
	Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson (Chuck)
	Sherlock (David)
	i3 (Sam)

Book Club
Refactoring: Ruby Edition: Ruby Edition (Addison-Wesley Professional Ruby Series) by Jay Fields, Shane Harvie, Martin Fowler, and Kent Beck
Refactoring in Ruby by William C. Wake and Kevin Rutherford
Next Week
Scaling Rails with Steve Corona
Transcript
AVDI:  I’m just imagining some horrible Australian creature is chewing on the wires right now.

JAMES:  [Chuckles]



[This episode is sponsored by Rackspace. Are you looking for a place to host your latest creation? Want terrific support, high performance all backed by the largest open source cloud? What if you could try it for free? Try out Rackspace at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace and get a $300 credit over six months. That’s $50 per month at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace.]

[Snap is a hosted CI and continuous delivery services that goes far beyond letting you do continuous deployment. Snap’s first class support for deployment pipelines lets you push any healthy build to multiple environments automatically and on demand. This means with Snap, you can deploy your staging environment today. Verify it works and later deploy the exact same build to production. Snap deploys your application to cloud services like Heroku, Digital Ocean, AWS, and many, many more. You can also use Snap to push your gems to RubyGems. Best of all, setting up your build is simple and intuitive. Try Snap free for 30 days. Sign up at SnapCI.com/RubyRogues.]

CHUCK:  Hey everybody and welcome to episode 161 of the Ruby Rogues Podcast. This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Good morning, or afternoon. I’m so confused.

CHUCK:  Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Hello, hello.

CHUCK:  David Brady.

DAVID:  You can build all of the logical gates out of NANDs, which means that all of computer science is based on the theory that two wrongs do make a right.

JAMES:  [Chuckles]

CHUCK:  I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.TV. And this week we have a special guest and that’s Sam Saffron.

SAM:  Good morning from Australia.

CHUCK:  So, we’ve had you on the show twice already?

SAM:  Once.

CHUCK:  Just once?

SAM:  Yeah.

JAMES:  Yeah. We were talking about Discourse.

SAM:  We were talking about Discourse. It’s a very [inaudible]…

CHUCK:  Well, having Jeff is like having you twice, right?

SAM:  [Chuckles]

DAVID:  Nobody’s going to touch the ‘it felt like twice’ joke? We’re all just going to leave that?

[Laughter]

JAMES:  Yeah, we’re just going to leave that.

DAVID:  This is actually my first time meeting you, Sam. So, welcome.

SAM:  Ah,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:12:25</itunes:duration>
	</item>