<item>
		<title>162 RR Scaling Rails with Steve Corona</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/162-rr-scaling-rails-with-steve-corona/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/162-rr-scaling-rails-with-steve-corona/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 13:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1896</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Steve Corona (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Discussion 01:38 &#8211; Steve Corona Introduction BigCommerce 01:57 &#8211; Twitpic Start Growth Scaling 03:51 &#8211; Learning on the Job vs. Skills and Experience 04:31 &#8211; Scaling 05:16 &#8211; TwitPic as Rails Application [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/162-rr-scaling-rails-with-steve-corona/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR162ScalingRails.mp3" length="61931674" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Steve Corona (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) - Discussion 01:38 - Steve Corona Introduction   BigCommerce - 01:57 - Twitpic </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Steve Corona (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)

Discussion
01:38 - Steve Corona Introduction


	BigCommerce

01:57 - Twitpic


	Start
	Growth
	Scaling

03:51 - Learning on the Job vs. Skills and Experience
04:31 - Scaling
05:16 - TwitPic as Rails Application


	PHP to Rails
	Coding
	Records/Database Issues

10:19 - Thumbnail API’s
10:58 - Restoring and Migrating Data


	Read-Only Functionality

12:02 - MySQL


	Building Apps
	Converting Tables

13:40 - Data Migration Timeline


	Rewriting PHP
	Creating Framework
	Converting to Rails

16:45 - Programmer vs. API Builder Mindset
17:30 - Go
17:31 - Node 
18:24 - JRuby


	JVM
	Tomcat
	GlassFish

21:34 - TorqueBox
23:12 - Background Functionality
26:27 - async
28:40 - Bajillion Different Queueing Servers
29:48 - Resque
29:57 - Github: Introducing Resque
32:41 - Turning Things Around


	JRuby

32:57 - Is Ruby Fast Yet?


	Number of Threads
	JVM Garbage Collection
	Testing
	Unicorn
	Puma
	Passenger

40:49 - Algorithms
43:09 - N+1 in Rails
45:35 - Micro-Optimizations
51:26 - Profiler Tools
51:45 - statsd


	Data Aggregation

53:01 - New Relic

Picks

	Zurb: Foundation (Avdi)
	bigfootjs (Avdi)
	Bower (Avdi)
	#GIRLBOSS by Sophia Amoruso (Saron)
	808 Cube (Saron)
	Dan McClain: Avoid Rails When Generating JSON responses with PostgreSQL (James)
	ScottBradleeLovesYa (James)
	Consul (Steve)
	NSQ Docs (Steve)
	The War of Art by Steven Pressfield (Steve)

Book Club
Refactoring: Ruby Edition: Ruby Edition (Addison-Wesley Professional Ruby Series) by Jay Fields, Shane Harvie, Martin Fowler, and Kent Beck
Refactoring in Ruby by William C. Wake and Kevin Rutherford
Next Week
Education with Coraline Ada Ehmke and Katrina Owen
Transcript


[This episode is sponsored by Rackspace. Are you looking for a place to host your latest creation? Want terrific support, high performance all backed by the largest open source cloud? What if you could try it for free? Try out Rackspace at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace and get a $300 credit over six months. That’s $50 per month at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace.]

[Snap is a hosted CI and continuous delivery services that goes far beyond letting you do continuous deployment. Snap’s first class support for deployment pipelines lets you push any healthy build to multiple environments automatically and on demand. This means with Snap, you can deploy your staging environment today. Verify it works and later deploy the exact same build to production. Snap deploys your application to cloud services like Heroku, Digital Ocean, AWS, and many, many more. You can also use Snap to push your gems to RubyGems. Best of all, setting up your build is simple and intuitive. Try Snap free for 30 days. Sign up at SnapCI.com/RubyRogues.]

JAMES:  Hello everyone and welcome to episode 162 of the Ruby Rogues Podcast. Chuck is out today, so I’m James Gray and I’ll be your host. With me today are Avdi Grimm…

AVDI:  Hello from Pennsylvania.

JAMES:  Saron Yitbarek.

SARON:  You said my name correctly. I’m very proud of you.

JAMES:  [Chuckles] I practiced.

[Chuckles]

JAMES:  And with us today, a special guest, Steve Corona.

STEVE:  Hey, thanks for having me on. I’m really excited to [help] you guys.

JAMES:  Thanks for taking the time. We appreciate it. Steve, since this is the first time you’ve been on, do you want to introduce yourself?

STEVE:  Sure, yeah. So, I’m Steve Corona. I was CTO of Twitpic, the big photo sharing app for twitter that everyone has used or heard about. Did that for a couple of years, and now I’m at a startup in San Francisco called BigCommerce. And I’m the principal architect there.

JAMES:  Wow, cool. So, Twitpic, that’s why we asked you to come on today. It turned out to be kind of a big deal, didn’t it?

STEVE:  Yeah,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:04:31</itunes:duration>
	</item>