<item>
		<title>163 RR Education with Coraline Ada Ehmke and Katrina Owen</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/163-rr-education-with-coraline-ada-ehmke-and-katrina-owen/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/163-rr-education-with-coraline-ada-ehmke-and-katrina-owen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coraline Ada Ehmke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saron Yitbarek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1901</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Coraline Ada Ehmke (twitter github blog) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:44 &#8211; Coraline Ada Ehmke Introduction Instructure 02:30 &#8211; Katrina Owen [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/163-rr-education-with-coraline-ada-ehmke-and-katrina-owen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR163Education.mp3" length="73292240" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Coraline Ada Ehmke (twitter github blog)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Coraline Ada Ehmke (twitter github blog)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:44 - Coraline Ada Ehmke Introduction


	Instructure

02:30 - Katrina Owen Introduction


	Splice
	Katrina at Rails 2013

05:00 - Katrina’s Teaching Tactics


	Blaise Pascal quote
	People Who Want To Learn
	The Flatiron School

12:14 - Dealing With People


	RailsConf 2014 - Artisans and Apprentices by Coraline Ada Ehmke

14:47 - Mentorship/Mastery


	Dev Bootcamp / @DevBootcamp
	@feministy
	Mastery by Robert Greene
	Socratic Method
	Autocratic

23:07 - Responsibilities to Community
24:47 - Organizations/Meetups


	ChicagoRuby
	Women Who Code
	Girl Develop It
	Chicago Women Developers
	LGBT Community Chicago
	“Don’t Be An Asshole” - The Flatiron School
	This American Life Episode #370: Ruining It for the Rest of Us

29:26 - “Bad Apples”
34:26 - Mentor/Teacher Relationships


	Apprenticeship Patterns: Guidance for the Aspiring Software Craftsman by Dave Hoover
	Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andy Hunt
	Dreyfus Scale

38:20 - Paid Coaching


	AirPair

42:50 - Direct vs. Indirect Mentorship


	Professor Mark Andre
	“Weaponizing Goodwill”
	The "Clever Hans" Effect
	Carol Dweck

53:30 - Bringing Up Junior Developers


	Saron Code Club Talk at RailsConf
	Code Club
	Dan Kubb
	Erik Michaels-Ober
	Myron Marston
	Markus Shirp
	Exercism

01:01:59 - Putting Code Online

See Also
James' and David's Code Reading Session: Ruby Code Reading: Equalizer and Concord

Picks

	Inch Pages: Documentation badges for Ruby projects (James)
	Shields.io (James)
	Hush (Remastered) Yo-Yo Ma (James)
	Prelude For Emacs (David)
	Charles Web Debugging Proxy  (David)
	Design for Hackers: Reverse Engineering Beauty by David Kadavy (Saron)
	Brain Rules for Baby (Updated and Expanded): How to Raise a Smart and Happy Child from Zero to Five by John Medina
	Drive: The Surprising Truth About What Motivates by Daniel H. Pink
	Slim (Avdi)
	Tab Coral for Chrome
	Apprenticeship Patterns By Dave Hoover and Adewale Oshineye (Coraline)
	ATUnit (Coraline)
	15 Sorting Algorithms in 6 Minutes (Katrina)
	Visualizing Git Concepts with D3 (Katrina)
	[Linux.conf.au 2013] - Git For Ages 4 And Up (Katrina)
	Janet Lansbury: Don't Stand Me Up (Katrina)
	[Picture] Katrina's Niece (Katrina)

Book Club
Refactoring: Ruby Edition: Ruby Edition (Addison-Wesley Professional Ruby Series) by Jay Fields, Shane Harvie, Martin Fowler, and Kent Beck
Refactoring in Ruby by William C. Wake and Kevin Rutherford
Next Week
Staying Sharp with Dave Thomas
Transcript
KATRINA:  I just have to go tweet an overheard. I’ll be right back.

[Laughter]



[This episode is sponsored by Rackspace. Are you looking for a place to host your latest creation? Want terrific support, high performance all backed by the largest open source cloud? What if you could try it for free? Try out Rackspace at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace and get a $300 credit over six months. That’s $50 per month at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace.]

[Snap is a hosted CI and continuous delivery services that goes far beyond letting you do continuous deployment. Snap’s first class support for deployment pipelines lets you push any healthy build to multiple environments automatically and on demand. This means with Snap, you can deploy your staging environment today. Verify it works and later deploy the exact same build to production. Snap deploys your application to cloud services like Heroku, Digital Ocean, AWS, and many, many more. You can also use Snap to push your gems to RubyGems. Best of all, setting up your build is simple and intuitive. Try Snap free for 30 days.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:16:21</itunes:duration>
	</item>