<item>
		<title>164 RR Staying Sharp with Dave Thomas</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/164-rr-staying-sharp-with-dave-thomas/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/164-rr-staying-sharp-with-dave-thomas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Thomas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saron Yitbarek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1918</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Dave Thomas (twitter blog) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:57 &#8211; Dave Thomas Introduction The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master by Dave [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/164-rr-staying-sharp-with-dave-thomas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/164StayingSharp.mp3" length="74061683" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Dave Thomas (twitter blog)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Co...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Dave Thomas (twitter blog)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:57 - Dave Thomas Introduction

	The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master by Dave Thomas
	The Agile Manifesto
	The Pickaxe Book

03:14 - Changing the Writing of Codes


	Clojure
	Elixir
	Programming Elixir: Functional |&gt; Concurrent |&gt; Pragmatic |&gt; Fun by Dave Thomas

06:37 - New Languages vs. Current Languages
07:42 - Erlang vs Elixir


	Mostly Erlang
	Erlang
	Prolog
	Haskell
	OGP
	Erlang gen-servers

09:07 - C and C++


	Class Construction in C and C++: Object-Oriented Programming Fundamentals by Roger Sessions
	Encapsulation
	Inheritance
	Struct
	Python
	C Macro
	Uni-code
	Method Definition

13:16 - Picking New Projects
17:14 - Dave Thomas in Texas, September 2014- Upcoming Events


	Markdown

17:56 - Pattern Matching


	Lazy Streams
	Class-based Programming (OO)
	Camel
	JavaScript Jabber Episode 061- Functional Reactive Programming

19:41 - Agile and Agility Principles


	Dave Thomas: Agile Is Dead (Long Live Agility)
	Scrum

22:19 - Abandoning Agile for Agility
25:41 - Measuring Success
28:49 - Writing Tests vs. Not Writing Tests


	Ruby Rails Conf 2014 - DHH Keynote David Heinemeier Hansson
	TDD
	API’s (expressive API’s)
	Regression
	Deploying
	Erlang OTP
	Ruby Rogues Episode 162- Scaling Rails
	Wicked Problem
	PCI Compliance

44:46 - Breaking Usual Programming Models
46:27 - Using Ruby Unconventionally


	Pacemaker

47:55 - Jumping Into New Languages


	Pseudoscience (see David’s picks)
	Go
	Dart
	OpenGL

54:31 - When To Change

Picks

	Dart for Hipsters by Chris Strom (James)
	The Prose Garden (James)
	A Gorgeous Woman Shakes Her Body On Stage ... And The Crowd Goes Wild (James)
	Something Ventured (Saron)
	fake_braintree (Saron)
	Bit-Shadow Machine (Saron)
	Bruce F. Webster: The Wetware Crisis: the Thermocline of Truth (Avdi)
	XML (Avdi)
	TorGuard (Avdi)
	unitwise (Avdi)
	Chrome Developer Tools (Chuck)
	Tab Wrangler (Chuck)
	Google Forum: comp.lang.misc
	Dad Is Fat by Jim Gaffigan (Chuck)
	Redbooth (Chuck)
	SDL MultiTerm Desktop (Dave)
	Camel-Markdown on Github (Dave)
	Artful Making: What Managers Need to Know About How Artists Work by Robert Austin, Lee Devin and Eric Schmidt (Dave)
	The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master by Andrew Hunt and Dave Thomas (David)
	Teach Yourself a New Programming Language in 21 Minutes (Or 2-3 Years, It Depends) from David's own blog, "Heart, Mind, and Code" (David)
	The Pseudoscience Wars: Immanuel Velikovsky and the Birth of the Modern Fringe by Michael D. Gordin (David)

Book Club
Refactoring: Ruby Edition: Ruby Edition (Addison-Wesley Professional Ruby Series) by Jay Fields, Shane Harvie, Martin Fowler, and Kent Beck
Refactoring in Ruby by William C. Wake and Kevin Rutherford
Next Week
Systems Programming Tricks with Julia Evans
Transcript
DAVE:  Yeah. I’m jolly good, y’all. 
[Laughter]

[This episode is sponsored by Rackspace. Are you looking for a place to host your latest creation? Want terrific support, high performance all backed by the largest open source cloud? What if you could try it for free? Try out Rackspace at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace and get a $300 credit over six months. That’s $50 per month at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace.]
[Snap is a hosted CI and continuous delivery services that goes far beyond letting you do continuous deployment. Snap’s first class support for deployment pipelines lets you push any healthy build to multiple environments automatically and on demand. This means with Snap, you can deploy your staging environment today. Verify it works and later deploy the exact same build to production.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:17:09</itunes:duration>
	</item>