<item>
		<title>175 RR Civic Hacking with William Jeffries</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/175-rr-civic-hacking-with-william-jeffries/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/175-rr-civic-hacking-with-william-jeffries/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 16:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saron Yitbarek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[William Jeffries]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=2011</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel William Jeffries (twitter linkedin) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 02:27 &#8211; William Jeffries SunGard Consulting Services Heat Seek NYC Heat Seek Kickstarter Campaign 02:53 &#8211; How Heat Seek Works 05:17 &#8211; An Idea is Born The Flatiron School Supermechanical Twine Tristen Siegel 06:53 &#8211; [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/175-rr-civic-hacking-with-william-jeffries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR175CivicHacking.mp3" length="40183588" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  William Jeffries (twitter linkedin)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) - Discussion 02:27 - William Jeffries - </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	William Jeffries (twitter linkedin)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
02:27 - William Jeffries

	SunGard Consulting Services
	Heat Seek NYC
	Heat Seek Kickstarter Campaign

02:53 - How Heat Seek Works

05:17 - An Idea is Born

	The Flatiron School
	Supermechanical Twine
	Tristen Siegel

06:53 - Getting Funded

	Heat Seek Kickstarter Campaign
	NYC BigApps

07:53 - Working with the Government

	New York Tech Meetup
	[TechPresident] De Blasio Names Minerva Tantoco First New York City CTO
	NYCHA
	NYC HPD (Housing Department)
	NYCEDC

11:39 - Challenges

	Hardware Contributions
	Code For America

	Textizen
	SeeClickFix
	Engage

	Catarse





14:00 - How the Sensors Work

	Urban Justice Center

15:03 - How Heat Seek Helps in Court

	Prima Facie

15:52 - Building the Cold Map

	Leaflet.js

16:44 - Restrictions and Government Data

	NYC Open Data
	311

18:04 - Technological Hurdles, Using Ruby, and Choosing Other Tech Tools

	Sensors
	Raspberry Pi
	DigiMesh

22:00 - Data

25:21 - Getting Ready for this Upcoming Winter &amp; Distributing Sensors

26:59 - Getting Involved in “Civic Hacking”

	The Environmental Performance Index (EPI)
	Code For America

See Also

	William and Tristan Present Heat Seek NYC at New York Tech Meetup
	Heat Seek NYC Aims to Keep the City Warm with Code
	[The Flatiron School] Project Recap: Heat Seek NYC
	[WIRED] How to Use the Internet of Things to Fight Slumlords

Picks

	Meet the Ipsums (Saron)
	4 ways to create CSS that's modular and scalable (Saron)
	CodeNewbie Podcast: Episode 1 - Bootcamps, Water Coolers and Hiring Devs (Saron)
	typing.io (Avdi)
	GelPro (Avdi)
	Boomerang for Gmail (Chuck)
	Think and Grow Rich by Napoleon Hill (Chuck)
	The Iron Druid Chronicles (Chuck)
	Polymer Web Components (William)

	JavaScript Jabber Episode #120: Google Polymer with Rob Dodson and Eric Bidelman


	NYC Department of Housing Preservation &amp; Development (William)
	Flatiron After School (William)

Book Club
Refactoring: Ruby Edition: Ruby Edition (Addison-Wesley Professional Ruby Series) by Jay Fields, Shane Harvie, Martin Fowler, and Kent Beck
Refactoring in Ruby by William C. Wake and Kevin Rutherford

Next Week
Rails as an SOA Client with Pete Hodgson
Transcript

[This episode is sponsored by Rackspace. Are you looking for a place to host your latest creation? Want terrific support, high performance all backed by the largest open source cloud? What if you could try it for free? Try out Rackspace at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace and get a $300 credit over six months. That’s $50 per month at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace.]
[This episode is sponsored by Codeship.io. Don’t you wish you could simply deploy your code every time your tests pass? Wouldn’t it be nice if it were tied into a nice continuous integration system? That’s Codeship. They run your code. If all your tests pass, they deploy your code automatically. For fuss-free continuous delivery, check them out at Codeship.io, continuous delivery made simple.]
[This episode is sponsored by Hired.com. Every week on Hired, they run an auction where over a thousand tech companies in San Francisco, New York, and L.A. bid on Ruby developers, providing them with salary and equity upfront. The average Ruby developer gets an average of 5 to 15 introductory offers and an average salary offer of $130,000 a year. Users can either accept an offer and go right into interviewing with the company or deny them without any continuing obligations. It’s totally free for users. And when you’re hired, they also give you a $2,000 signing bonus as a thank you for using them. But if you use the Ruby Rogues link, you’ll get a $4,000 bonus instead. Finally, if you’re not looking for a job and know someone who is, you can refer them to Hired and get a $1,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>41:51</itunes:duration>
	</item>