<item>
		<title>177 RR Creativity and Technology</title>
		<link>http://rubyrogues.com/177-rr-creativity-and-technology/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/177-rr-creativity-and-technology/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 13:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saron Yitbarek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=2032</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Panel Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 03:40 &#8211; Cartooning Saron’s Cartoons 04:39 &#8211; What is “Creativity” and “Being Creative”? Purpose Relaxing Becoming a Writer by Dorothea Brande Inspiration 09:12 &#8211; Creativity and Coding Stimulation “The Principle of Least Surprise” 18:40 &#8211; [&#8230;]]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/177-rr-creativity-and-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR177Creativity.mp3" length="74159480" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) - Discussion 03:40 - Cartooning - </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Saron Yitbarek (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
03:40 - Cartooning

	Saron’s Cartoons

04:39 - What is “Creativity” and “Being Creative”?

	Purpose
	Relaxing
	Becoming a Writer by Dorothea Brande
	Inspiration

09:12 - Creativity and Coding

	Stimulation
	“The Principle of Least Surprise”

18:40 - Avoidance and Procrastination

	Type A People vs Type B People

22:18 - Increasing Creativity

	exercism.io

23:35 - What is “Creativity”?

	Self-Comparison
	RubyTapas
	Novelty
	Productivity &amp; Invention
	Getting Ideas

31:02 - Creative Endeavours

	Creating a Language
	Inventing
	Everything is a Remix
	“Manufacturing Serendipity”

33:53 - Running Out of Ideas

	“I write only when inspiration strikes. Fortunately it strikes every morning at nine o'clock sharp.” - W. Somerset Maugham
	National Novel Writing Month (NaNoWriMo)

37:38 - Stifling Creativity &amp; Putting “Crap” Out There

	Studying Other People’s Work

41:17 - Left Brain vs Right Brain

46:03 - Exploring Creativity

47:45 - How Do You Become Creative?

	David’s Paperclip Example
	Saron’s Candle on the Wall Example
	Drive by Dan Pink
	Functional Fixedness
	Global Day of Coderetreat
	Putting Yourself Under Stress/Duress

01:01:42 - Contribute to Open Source
Picks

	Mass Effect 3 - Shepard’s Indoctrination (David)
	Fourplay IPA (Avdi)
	Circa (Avdi)
	Eat a Pumpkin (Saron)
	Fixed Mindset vs. Growth Mindset (Saron)
	Spinning RGB LED Ball II (Saron)
	The Code Newbie Discourse Page (Saron)
	Think and Grow Rich: The Landmark Bestseller - Now Revised and Updated for the 21st Century by Napoleon Hill (Chuck)
	Exercise (Chuck)

Book Club
Refactoring: Ruby Edition: Ruby Edition (Addison-Wesley Professional Ruby Series) by Jay Fields, Shane Harvie, Martin Fowler, and Kent Beck
Refactoring in Ruby by William C. Wake and Kevin Rutherford

Transcript
DAVID:  So, why not make the friend and take the friendship and make it awkward?

[This episode is sponsored by Rackspace. Are you looking for a place to host your latest creation? Want terrific support, high performance all backed by the largest open source cloud? What if you could try it for free? Try out Rackspace at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace and get a $300 credit over six months. That’s $50 per month at RubyRogues.com/Rackspace.]
[This episode is sponsored by Codeship.io. Don’t you wish you could simply deploy your code every time your tests pass? Wouldn’t it be nice if it were tied into a nice continuous integration system? That’s Codeship. They run your code. If all your tests pass, they deploy your code automatically. For fuss-free continuous delivery, check them out at Codeship.io, continuous delivery made simple.]
[This episode is sponsored by Hired.com. Every week on Hired, they run an auction where over a thousand tech companies in San Francisco, New York, and L.A. bid on Ruby developers, providing them with salary and equity upfront. The average Ruby developer gets an average of 5 to 15 introductory offers and an average salary offer of $130,000 a year. Users can either accept an offer and go right into interviewing with the company or deny them without any continuing obligations. It’s totally free for users. And when you’re hired, they also give you a $2,000 signing bonus as a thank you for using them. But if you use the Ruby Rogues link, you’ll get a $4,000 bonus instead. Finally, if you’re not looking for a job and know someone who is, you can refer them to Hired and get a $1,337 bonus if they accept a job. Go sign up at Hired.com/RubyRoguesPodcast.]
[Snap is a hosted CI and continuous delivery that is simple and intuitive. Snap’s deployment pipelines deliver fast feedback and can push healthy builds to multiple environments automatically or on demand.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Charles Max Wood, James Edward Gray II, David Brady, Avdi Grimm, Josh Susser, Katrina Owen</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:17:15</itunes:duration>
	</item>