<item>
		<title>057 RR – Ruby Central</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/QKYihIqIId8/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/057-rr-rubycentral/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 03:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chad Fowler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evan Phoenix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=554</guid>
		<description>Panel Evan Phoenix (twitter github blog) Chad Fowler (twitter github chadfowler.com) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (blog witter github ADDcasts) James Edward Gray II (blog twitter github) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Discussion Chad Fowler doesn&amp;#8217;t listen to podcasts Learning sign language Evil League of Evil Ruby Central RubyConf RailsConf RailsConf Europe RubyCon vs. RubyConf/Ruby Central RubyForge Gforge RAA RAA.SUCC RubyGems.org PDI as a career choice JavaCentral? [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/QKYihIqIId8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/057-rr-rubycentral/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR057RubyCentral.mp3" length="77032094" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Evan Phoenix (twitter github blog)   Chad Fowler (twitter github chadfowler.com)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (blog witter github ADDcasts)   James Edward Gray II (blog twitter github) </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Evan Phoenix (twitter github blog)
	Chad Fowler (twitter github chadfowler.com)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (blog witter github ADDcasts)
	James Edward Gray II (blog twitter github)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)

Discussion

	Chad Fowler doesn't listen to podcasts
	Learning sign language
	Evil League of Evil Ruby Central
	RubyConf
	RailsConf
	RailsConf Europe
	RubyCon vs. RubyConf/Ruby Central
	RubyForge
	Gforge
	RAA
	RAA.SUCC
	RubyGems.org
	PDI as a career choice
	JavaCentral? PythonCentral?
	Sun Oracle (Snoracle)
	Python Software Foundation
	Perl Software Foundation
	Organizing conferences make people go crazy
	RubyCentral encouraged the formation of regional conferences
	ClassBox
	Ruby/Rails community can risk echochamber/groupthink
	The wrong style of OO
	"Programmers have a tendency to build castles in the sky."
	"Overdecomplecting"
	Moving RubyCentral forward
	RubyCentral-like site for cataloging regional conferences - Josh Susser, PDI

Picks

	Loratdine Alergy Tablets (Generic Claritin) (Evan)
	RubyLVM (Evan)
	Legend of Korra (Josh)
	SimpleForm (Josh)
	Go outside and play (David)
	Mosin Nagant (David)
	Trap and Skeet Shooting in San Francisco (David)
	Hunter's Education (David)
	Badminton (Avdi)
	Diablo III (James)
	Gratuitous Tank Battles (James)
	Esoteric Programming Languages by David Morgan Marr (Chad)
	Let Over Lambda (Chad)

Transcript
CHAD: Oh! That’s Avdi’s voice that sounds so amazing, isn’t it?
AVDI: (laughs) That’s going to have to go in and overheard.

EVAN: It does lend itself to a good sort of like “sensual intro”.

[laughter]

AVDI: We should do the Ruby Shoe Diaries.

JAMES: Ruby Shoe Diaries.



[This episode is sponsored by railsthemes.com. Have a website only a mother could love? Then you need a theme. Go to railsthemes.com and sign up for our early access and when they release, you’ll be able to check out and use their themes on your Rails App.]

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to rubyrogues.com/newrelic.]

JAMES: Hey everybody! Welcome to the Ruby Rogues podcast. This is Episode 57 and with us today we have Josh Susser.

JOSH: Hello! James just told me. Hey! Good Morning from San Francisco!

JAMES: You’re supposed to un-mute when you talk Josh.

JOSH: I know. I know. I must have got that wrong.

JAMES: I don’t know how many instructions do I have…

JOSH: Un-mute first and then talk.

JAMES: And we have…

JOSH: Moving right along.

JAMES: We have Avdi Grimm.

AVDI: Hi! This is Avdi. And James, please tell Josh that I’m not speaking to him because he insulted my hair.

JAMES: (Josh, Avdi’s not speaking to you.) And we have David Brady.

DAVID: Hey everybody! I’m back from vacation except that I carefully time my vacations to be between episodes and so I’m just still here.

JAMES: Just to be clear nobody has yet insulted David Brady’s hair this morning.

AVDI: I have had my hair pattern insulted several, several times.

JAMES: I’m James Edward Grey II. I’m standing in as host today because we’re minus our usual leader Chuck. But we have two guests today. We have Evan Phoenix who’s been on the show before. Hi Evan!

EVAN: Hi everybody from sunny Los Angeles.

JAMES: And we have Chad Fowler who admits he doesn’t listen to the show. Hi Chad!

CHAD: (laughs) Hello! But to be fair, I don’t listen to any podcast and I am in Washington, DC where it is tropical and hideous.

JAMES: I’m in Oklahoma where it’s hailing and taking out everybody’s power and stuff like that. So we’ll see how well this recording goes today.

DAVID: Chad, you don’t listen to podcast. In the pre-call you said that’s because you’re Amish.

CHAD: Kind of. Yeah. I mean essentially that’s what I meant but the way I said it was that I am unable to actually comprehend things when they’re spoken to me in large volumes.

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:04:12</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR057RubyCentral.mp3" fileSize="77032094" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/057-rr-rubycentral/</feedburner:origLink></item>