<item>
		<title>069 RR Therapeutic Refactoring with Katrina Owen</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/6rzeR5l4lPc/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/069-rr-therapeutic-refactoring-with-katrina-owen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=649</guid>
		<description>Panel Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (blog witter github ADDcasts) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp) James Edward Gray (blog twitter github) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Discussion Firefly Therapeutic Refactoring &amp;#8211; Katrina Owen Serenity Refactoring Livecoding at Talks: Trapeze Sans Net Refactoring makes you feel better Choke by Sian Beilock Test Driven Development [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/6rzeR5l4lPc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/069-rr-therapeutic-refactoring-with-katrina-owen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR069.mp3" length="83536214" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (blog witter github ADDcasts)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp)   James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)   Josh S...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel


	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (blog witter github ADDcasts)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Summer Camp)
	James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)


Discussion

	Firefly
	Therapeutic Refactoring - Katrina Owen
	Serenity
	Refactoring
	Livecoding at Talks: Trapeze Sans Net
	Refactoring makes you feel better
	Choke by Sian Beilock
	Test Driven Development (TDD)
	Bryan Takita RR Test Library
	rspec-fire
	Heckle
	Chartjunk
	The Visual Display of Quantitative Information by Edward Tufte
	Explicit Returns, Surprise Return!
	Getting Started with Refactoring - Pick Something Easy, Gain Confidence
	Red/Green Refactor
	Call a Method, Send a Message
	Step away from the computer.

Picks

	Rupa/z (Katrina)
	XUnit Test Patterns by Gerard Meszaros (Avdi)
	Mei Tai Child Carrier (Avdi)
	Practical Object Oriented Design in Ruby by Sandi Metz (Katrina)
	The Little Schemer by Daniel P. Friedman (Katrina)
	Pebblestack.org (Katrina)
	Hashrocket Lunch and Learn Video - Tests, Mocks, Dependency Injections - Sandi Metz (James)
	The Rational Optimist by Matt Ridley (James)
	Google Web Fonts (Josh)
	Math Video - Parabolas (Josh)
	Chirp (iPhone) (Josh)
	Fontsquirrel (Avdi)
	Encouraging Others Through Christ Podcast (Chuck)
	The $100 Startup by Chris Biligo (Chuck)

Transcript
JOSH: Katrina, do you know about the picks?

KATRINA: I do. I have like four lined up. If that's too many, I can reduce it.

JAMES: Not at all.

CHUCK: Four is good.

JOSH: You know 4 picks from you is probably about equal to one pick from David so...



[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to rubyrogues.com/newrelic.]

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built in version control and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to jetbrains.com/ruby.]

[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at bluebox.net.]

CHUCK: Hey everybody! And welcome to Episode 69 of the Ruby Rouges podcast. This week on our panel we have Avdi Grimm.

AVDI: Hello! Hello!

CHUCK: David Brady.

DAVID: Hey everybody! In honor of the Mass Effect 3 ending, I'm going to spend the last 10 minutes of this podcast showing you the ultimate way to repair your car!

CHUCK: Josh Susser.

JOSH: Here I come to save the day.

DAVID: Yey!

CHUCK: James Edward Grey.

JAMES: According to Twitter, I am the “laughing bird” of this podcast.

[laughter]

AVDI: Who is the drinking bird?

JOSH: That would be you!

DAVID: Is that your answer on Jeopardy?

CHUCK: I'm Charles Max Wood from devchat.tv and this week, we have a special guest and that's Katrina Owen.

KATRINA: Hello!

CHUCK: Since you’re new to the show, do you want to introduce yourself really quick?

KATRINA: Sure. I've been doing Ruby for about 2 years. I did this at a small product development company in Oslo, Norway.

CHUCK: Oh.

JOSH: What did you do before Ruby?

KATRINA: Do we have to talk about this?

[laughter]

JOSH: No.

JAMES: Oh! It's shameful.

CHUCK: She lives in the land of the chosen frozen. And she doesn't want to talk about what she did before Ruby.

KATRINA: So I actually, I can reveal that I wrote PHP for a fashion company in Los Angeles.

CHUCK: Wow.

JAMES: Way to find the pain point right off the bat, Josh.

[laughter]

DAVID: I am coming out of the cold but you moved to Norway.

KATRINA: Yeah, I've been back and forth a few times.

JOSH: Sorry about that Katrina. Welcome to the show! How are you today?

KATRINA: Thank you. I'm fine. How are you?

CHUCK: Aren’t we supposed to start the show off? Go on. So did you guys do anything interesting this week?

</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:09:37</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR069.mp3" fileSize="83536214" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/069-rr-therapeutic-refactoring-with-katrina-owen/</feedburner:origLink></item>