<item>
		<title>077 RR Complexity with Glenn Vanderburg</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/0RbqQimP4CE/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/077-rr-complexity-with-glenn-vanderburg/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glenn Vanderburg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=833</guid>
		<description>Panel Glenn Vanderburg (blog twitter Grasping Complexity with Both Hands) James Edward Gray (blog twitter github) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript) Discussion 01:41 &amp;#8211; Book Club &amp;#8211; Practical Object-Oriented Design in [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/0RbqQimP4CE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/077-rr-complexity-with-glenn-vanderburg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR077Complexity.mp3" length="66321055" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Glenn Vanderburg (blog twitter Grasping Complexity with Both Hands)   James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog) </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Glenn Vanderburg (blog twitter Grasping Complexity with Both Hands)
	James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript)

Discussion
01:41 - Book Club - Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby by Sandi Metz

	Interviewing: January 2nd
	Airing: January 9th

02:52 - Best of Parley

	All past guests/all future guests have joined the list!
	Benjamin Fleischer + RubyConf tips

04:18 - Ruby Nuby Project

	LAST DAY TO SUBMIT VIDEOS!
	Supporters: RubyMonk, RailsCasts, The Pragmatic Studio

05:29 - Grasping Complexity with Both Hands

	How to recognize genuinely complex problems and situations
	How to think clearly and make smart decisions
	Things tend to get complicated when people get involved

08:46 - Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams by Tom DeMarco and Timothy Lister

11:19 - No Silver Bullet --Essence and Accident in Software Engineering by Frederick P. Brooks, Jr.

13:04 - Learnable Programming: Designing a programming system for understanding programs by Bret Victor

16:05 - Science and ways of dealing with complex situations

18:20 - Bounded Complexity and Unbounded Complexity

23:41 - The Birthday Paradox

	Asking the right question

29:04 - Don’t try to make things NOT go wrong

34:35 - Communicating when something is complex

	Keeping multiple thoughts in your head
	Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andy Hunt

39:24 - Unit Testing


Proof

Relativity

Genetic algorithms and software evolution: Thomas S. Ray

Picks

	Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams by Tom DeMarco and Timothy Lister (Dave)
	The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business by Charles Duhigg (Dave)
	7 Patterns to Refactor Fat ActiveRecord Models: Bryan Helmkamp (Avdi)
	Giant Robots Smashing into other Giant Robots (James)
	RubyTapas (James)
	Awesome HD Slinky Slow-Mo (James)
	99 Life Hacks to make your life easier! (Josh)
	Looper (Josh)
	Robert A Heinlein: By His Own Bootstraps (Josh)
	Robert A Heinlein: All You Zombies (Josh)
	Primer (Avdi)
	Hexaflexagons (Avdi)
	Tweetbot for Mac (Chuck)
	Wicked Problems 1 (Glenn)
	Wicked Problems 2 (Glenn)
	Wicked Problems 3 (Glenn)
	On Bullshit by Harry Frankfurt (Glenn)
	Steven Berlin Johnson (Glenn)

Next Week

	Hexagonal Rails with Matt Wynne and Kevin Rutherford

Ruby Rogues Book Club
The next Ruby Rogues Book Club Pick will be Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby: An Agile Primer by Sandi Metz. We will be interviewing Sandi on January 2, 2013 with the episode airing January 9, 2013.

The publisher, Pearson/Addison-Wesley is offering a discount via InformIT.com.

	First create a user account: www.informit.com/join
	SAVE 40% When You Buy 2: www.informit.com/ruby
	Add books of choice to Shopping Cart, then enter the code SAVEONRUBY during Checkout
	(Includes FREE SHIPPING within the U.S.!)

Transcript 
JAMES: All right. So what are we talking about today? Are we talking about complexity?

JOSH: OK. So, do we have a drinking game for this? Like every time David uses the word “complecting”?

[laughter]



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at bluebox.net]

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to jetbrains.com/ruby]

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to rubyrogues.com/newrelic]

CHUCK: Hey everybody and welcome to episode 77 of the Ruby Rogues Podcast! This week on our panel we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES: Who are you people and why do you keep calling me?

CHUCK: Avdi Grimm.
</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:09:05</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR077Complexity.mp3" fileSize="66321055" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/077-rr-complexity-with-glenn-vanderburg/</feedburner:origLink></item>