<item>
		<title>082 RR Vagrant with Michael Ries</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/nkyDv_H7E2I/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/082-rr-vagrant-with-michael-ries/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Ries]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=952</guid>
		<description>Panel Michael Ries (twitter blog) James Edward Gray (blog twitter github) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript) Discussion 01:30 &amp;#8211; Best of Parley Our New Rogue: Katrina Owen by Josh Susser Ruby Nuby Challenge Winners: Elise Worthy, Erin [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/nkyDv_H7E2I" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/082-rr-vagrant-with-michael-ries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR082Vagrant.mp3" length="49377421" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Michael Ries (twitter blog)   James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript) - Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Michael Ries (twitter blog)
	James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript)

Discussion
01:30 - Best of Parley

	Our New Rogue: Katrina Owen by Josh Susser
	Ruby Nuby Challenge Winners: Elise Worthy, Erin Parker, Geoff Petrie, Matt Ruzicka

03:22 - Vagrant

	074 RR Developer Environments

04:44 - Setting up Vagrant

	Provisioners
	VirtualBox

Vagrantbox.es

09:31 - What does it matter if your developer environment is different from your production environment?


Multi-VM Environments

Bosh
	Chef

14:17 - Benefits and advantages of using Vagrant

18:41 - Multiple Machine Stacks

24:07 - Repackaging

	Puppet

25:17 - Shared images


vagrant-rails

rails-dev-box

27:09 - Does Vagrant run on Windows? 28:23 - Vagrant Gotchas


DNS issues

31:12 - IDEs, vim and TextMate
Picks

	Ubuntu (David)
	The Twelve-Factor App (David)
	5 Reasons You Should Use ri To Read Ruby Documentation by Jesse Storimer (James)
	TEDxToronto 2012 Talk - Ryan Creighton &amp; Cassandra Creighton (James)
	YAML::Store (Katrina)
	Pygments (Katrina)
	World Clock Meeting Planner (Katrina)
	gomtv.net - Starcraft2 Tournaments (Michael)
	Do a favor for someone at work that is hard to live with (Michael)
	Opening Keynote: Code Blindness by Michael Feathers (Michael)
	IOIO (Michael)
	iPhone 5 (Chuck)
	Omnifocus (Chuck)
	SpeakPipe (Chuck)

Send the RubyRogues a voice message!
Next Week
Decomposing Fat Models with Bryan Helmkamp
Book Club
The next Ruby Rogues Book Club Pick will be  Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby: An Agile Primer by Sandi Metz. We will be interviewing Sandi on January 2, 2013, with the episode airing January 9, 2013. The publisher, Pearson/Addison-Wesley is offering a discount via  InformIT.com.

	First create a user account:  www.informit.com/join
	SAVE 40% When You Buy 2:  www.informit.com/ruby
	Add books of choice to Shopping Cart, then enter the code SAVEONRUBY during Checkout
	(Includes FREE SHIPPING within the U.S.!)

Transcript
MICHAEL: Has anyone actually met David Brady’s wife -- and is she real?

CHUCK: Yes.

JAMES: That's an excellent question. Chuck claims she’s real, but that's as far as we know.

CHUCK: I can do one better. I have seen David Brady and his wife in a church.

[laughter]

DAVID: We were setting it on fire, but he did see us there.

[laughter]



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at bluebox.net]

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to jetbrains.com/ruby]

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to rubyrogues.com/newrelic]

CHUCK: Hey everybody and welcome to episode 82 of the Ruby Rogues podcast! This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES: Good morning everyone!

CHUCK: Katrina Owen.

KATRINA: Hello!

CHUCK: David Brady.

DAVID: Holy crap! Did you just say “Katrina Owen”?

CHUCK: And I'm Charles Max Wood from devchat.tv. We also have a special guest and that's Michael Ries.

MICHAEL: Yup. Good morning interwebs!

CHUCK: So we are gonna be talking about Vagrant – but before we get started, we are going to have a Best of Parley from James.

JAMES: Yeah. The cool thing about Parley this week (in my opinion) is that you can basically use it as the insider information channel on the Ruby Rogues. For example, if someday we were to bring on a new Rogue, it might just happen that we would mention it there. Another thing that's been announced there is the Ruby Nuby project winners -- which are Elise Worthy, Erin Parker,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>51:26</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR082Vagrant.mp3" fileSize="49377421" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/082-rr-vagrant-with-michael-ries/</feedburner:origLink></item>