<item>
		<title>074 RR Developer Environments</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/MSzo9dA7SIM/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/0074-rr-developer-environments/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=779</guid>
		<description>Panel Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) James Edward Gray (blog twitter github) David Brady (blog twitter github ADDcasts) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript) Discussion 02:05 &amp;#8211; Developer Environments 02:40 &amp;#8211; Standing desks Health benefits Physical fitness 04:51 &amp;#8211; Exercise balls Keeps core [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/MSzo9dA7SIM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/0074-rr-developer-environments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR074DeveloperEnvironments.mp3" length="45996540" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)   David Brady (blog twitter github ADDcasts)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript) - </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)
	David Brady (blog twitter github ADDcasts)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript)

Discussion
02:05 - Developer Environments

02:40 - Standing desks

	Health benefits
	Physical fitness

04:51 - Exercise balls

	Keeps core engaged
	Prevents slouching

06:29 - Uses for a Mac Pro

	Telepresence machine
	Main development machine

08:40 - Multiple monitors

11:25 - Background noise

	Podcasts
	Music

15:42 - General noise

17:43 - Working from different environments

	Restaurants
	Coffee shops
	Libraries

22:02 - Knowing what works for you and adapting your environment

23:18 - Office environments versus home environments

25:35 - Desks: cluttered/uncluttered

29:08 - Ergonomics


Split keyboards

Posture and positions

35:46 - Software and programs that contribute to productivity

	Balsamiq
	Skitch
	Pivotal Tracker
	Guard
	tmux
	Continuous Integration
	CCMenu

41:08 - Light


f.lux

Fluorescent lighting

Ambient lighting

Programming outside

Matte/Glossy displays

Screen brightness &amp; keyboard backlighting

48:50 - Contrast/color themes


Tomorrow theme

Zenburn

Molokai for Vim

Molokai for Emacs

OSX Dark Terminal Theme for Mac Snow Leopard

52:35 - Programming in Windows

55:37 - Mac vs Linux

Why Linux: Avdi Grimm
MacPorts
Homebrew

01:07:28 - Pomodoro Technique

	Pomodoro Technique Illustrated

Picks

	Vitamix 6300 (Dave)
	Xiki (Avdi)
	Star Trek: The Next Generation Season 8 on Twitter (Avdi)
	Hashrocket Lunch n' Learn - Defining Object-Oriented Design: Sandi Metz (James)
	Apple iTunes Match (James)
	The Trouble with the Electoral College: C.G.P. Grey (Josh)
	National Popular Vote Interstate Compact (Josh)
	Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby: Sandi Metz (Chuck)
	Ergotron Arm (Chuck)

Book Club Book Pick

	Service-Oriented Design with Ruby and Rails: Paul Dix

Transcript
JOSH: As everyone watches the Presidential Debates tonight and gets despondent over the state of national politics, I want you to contrast that with the terrible state of affairs here in San Francisco, where our huge political issue this week is the fact that one of the supervisors wants to ban public nudity to stop the old naked dudes from hanging out in the town square of Nicastro.

AVDI: Why is that a problem?

[laughter]

DAVID: All I want to know is are they going to do anything about the roller-skating hat cocker on the Embarcadero?



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by The Blue Box Group. Check them out at bluebox.net]

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great in line debugging tools, built in version control and intelligent code insight and refactorings, checkout RubyMine by going to jetbrains.com/ruby.]

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to rubyrogues.com/newrelic.]

CHUCK: Hey everybody and welcome to episode 74 of the Ruby Rogues Podcast. This week on our panel we have Josh Susser.

JOSH: Hey, good morning everyone!

CHUCK:  We have Avdi Grimm.

AVDI: Hey, this is Avdi, Head Chef at rubytapas.com.

CHUCK: We also have James Edward Gray.

JAMES: We have had complaints about our jokes, so I am not opening with a joke this time.

CHUCK: We also have David Brady.

DAVID: I just want to start with a warning, [unintelligible]

CHUCK: I am Charles Max Wood from devchat.tv. I am actually working on an introduction to CoffeeScript webinar or online training that I am going to be doing. You can get it at introtocoffeescript.eventbright.com. Alright, well so let’s get this started. So, we are going to be talking about our Development Environments.

JOSH: Do you mean IDEs?

[laughter]

CHUCK: Yeah,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:22:36</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR074DeveloperEnvironments.mp3" fileSize="45996540" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/0074-rr-developer-environments/</feedburner:origLink></item>