<item>
		<title>094 RR Robust Ruby with Ara T. Howard</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/DZca8XzaRHU/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/094-rr-robust-ruby-with-ara-t-howard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ara T. Howard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Brady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katrina Owen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=1166</guid>
		<description>Panel Ara T. Howard (twitter github mostlovelyart) James Edward Gray (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts) Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up) Discussion 01:48 &amp;#8211; Ara T. Howard Introduction CTO of codeforpeople.com dojo4 NOAA &amp;#8211; [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/DZca8XzaRHU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/094-rr-robust-ruby-with-ara-t-howard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR094AraTHoward.mp3" length="68142527" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Ara T. Howard (twitter github mostlovelyart)   James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)   Katrina Owen (twitter github blog) </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Ara T. Howard (twitter github mostlovelyart)
	James Edward Gray (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	David Brady (twitter github blog ADDcasts)
	Katrina Owen (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Rails Ramp Up)

Discussion
01:48 - Ara T. Howard Introduction

	CTO of codeforpeople.com
	dojo4
	NOAA - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration
	ahoward / map
	ahoward / dao
	ahoward / slave

10:11 - ahoward / rq (Ruby Queue)

	Jeremy Hinegardner (@copiousfreetime)
	NOAA Jet Supercomputer
	NOAA National Geophysical Data Center (NGDC)
	Change Detection In Satellite Observed Change Detection In Satellite Observed Nighttime Lights: 1992 - 2003

15:04 - Hurricane Katrina Image Processing

	Linux Clustering with Ruby Queue: Small Is Beautiful - Ara T. Howard
	Katrina images generated with Ruby - Ara T. Howard
	Google Search: katrina dmsp ara t. howard results
	Guy Decoux

24:21 - Making Ruby Robust

	SQLite
	Dining Philosophers Problem
	Caching
	Ruby on Rails Guides: Asset Pipeline

33:00 - Thinking and mapping problems (Design)

	An XP Guy
	Exceptional Ruby by Avdi Grimm
	rescue Object vs rescue Exception

48:53 - Testing and Documentation

	ahoward / rego
	ahoward / testy
	Readme Driven Development - Tom Preston-Werner

Picks

	Celluloid: Fix some potential concurrent mutation problems (Tony Arcieri) (James)
	Sentinels of the Multiverse (James)
	Ara T. Howard Github Repositories (Avdi)
	Index of /lib/ruby (Avdi)
	Tom Bihn (Avdi)
	Google Search: katrina dmsp ara t. howard results (David)
	codeforpeople.com/katrina/ (David)
	Ashe Dryden / @ashedryden (David)
	ahoward / main (Katrina)
	C.G.P. Grey (Katrina)
	Designer Habitat - Floating Adjustable Shelf Wall Mount Bracket (Chuck)
	Parade of Homes (Chuck)
	Gödel's incompleteness theorems (Ara)
	How to Practice : The Way to a Meaningful Life by Dalai Lama (Ara)
	Artsy: What did the Sphinx Say? (Ara)

Book Club
Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture by Martin Fowler: Read along with us! We will be discussing the book with Martin himself and the episode will air on Wednesday, March 20th, 2013.
Next Week
People and Team Dynamics with Joe O'Brien
Transcript
DAVID:  Well, my mom doesn’t remember Woodstock, which means she was there.

[Laughter]

ARA:  Oh, that’s hilarious.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at  BlueBox.net.] 

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to  RubyRogues.com/NewRelic.] 

[This episode is brought to you by WAZA, Heroku’s one day celebration of art and technique. Join Matz, Aaron Patterson, and more on February 28th in San Francisco. Use exclusive code ruby-rogues-13 for $50 off registration at WAZA.Heroku.com.] 

CHUCK:  Hey, everybody and welcome to Episode 94 of the Ruby Rogues podcast. This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JAMES:  Hello everyone.

CHUCK:  Avdi Grimm.

AVDI:  Hey from Pennsylvania.

CHUCK:  David Brady.

DAVID:  Hey everybody. I’m really excited to be here today because I’ve been stalking Ara for about seven years now. And the closest I’ve come is I filled in for him at MountWest Ruby Conf last year when he couldn’t make it to the conference. I took his speaker slot.

CHUCK:  So, the closest you’ve ever gotten is him not being there.

DAVID:  Yes.

[Laughter]

CHUCK:  Alright. We also have Katrina Owen.

KATRINA:  Hi, I’m very excited to be here today because I’ve missed the last two episodes due to being stuck in a time travel paradox.

CHUCK:  Wow!

JAMES:  Ouch!

CHUCK:  I’m Charles Max Wood from DevChat.tv. You have one week left to sign up for Rails Ramp Up. And we have a special guest. That is Ara T. Howard. Is that how you want to be introduced?

ARA:  That will do just fine.

CHUCK:  Alright. Since you haven’t been on the show before,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:10:59</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR094AraTHoward.mp3" fileSize="68142527" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/094-rr-robust-ruby-with-ara-t-howard/</feedburner:origLink></item>