<item>
		<title>080 RR Practical Metaprogramming with Steven Harms</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/GRmp_u3lzMM/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/080-rr-practical-metaprogramming-with-steven-harms/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steven Harms]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=879</guid>
		<description>Panel Steven Harms (twitter github blog) James Edward Gray (blog twitter github) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript) Discussion 02:20 &amp;#8211; Best of Parley Functional Programming for the Object-Oriented Programmer by Andy Lindeman 03:55 &amp;#8211; Practical metaprogramming 012 [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/GRmp_u3lzMM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/080-rr-practical-metaprogramming-with-steven-harms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR080PracticalMetaProgramming.mp3" length="69705288" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Steven Harms (twitter github blog)   James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript) - Discussion </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Steven Harms (twitter github blog)
	James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript)

Discussion
02:20 - Best of Parley

	Functional Programming for the Object-Oriented Programmer by Andy Lindeman

03:55 - Practical metaprogramming

	012 RR Metaprogramming in Ruby
	Practical Meta Programming Modeling Thought by Steven Harms
	RubyTapas: 011 Method and Message

08:54 - Steven Harms’ definition of metaprogramming

	Redirection
	At run time

13:23 - Decorator patterns

15:22 - Two categories of metaprogramming

19:13 - Ruby 2.0 Module#prepend

22:12 - Keys to understanding metaprogramming

	Inheritance chain
	Metaprogramming Ruby: Program Like the Ruby Pros by Paolo Perrotta
	Redirect messages by defining things (def)

26:43 - undef method vs remove method

30:12 - Making code metaprogrammable


Find by email

43:02 - Using metaprogramming


Dynamic finders

Ambiguity

49:29 - How to level up in metaprogramming

51:15 - Adding methods to objects and putting them in a module


Polite metaprogramming

Picks


harukizaemon / hamster (James)

iTunes Match (James)

Rebuilding Rails by Noah Gibbs (Avdi)

Aardman Animations (Avdi)

The Insufficiency of Good Design: Sarah Mei (Josh)

Toward a Design for Ruby: Brian Ford (Josh)

Powers Vol. 1: Who Killed Retro Girl? by Michael Avon Oeming (Josh)

Shop It To Me (Steven)

Ember.js (Steven)

fastrAck (Steven)

GIFL (Steven)

Social Engagement (Steven)

The Ruby Object Model and Metaprogramming by Dave Thomas (Chuck)

New Media Expo 2013 (Discount code Wood20) (Chuck)

Next Week


Rails 4 with Aaron Patterson

Book Club
The next Ruby Rogues Book Club Pick will be Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby: An Agile Primer by Sandi Metz. We will be interviewing Sandi on January 2, 2013, with the episode airing January 9, 2013. The publisher, Pearson/Addison-Wesley is offering a discount via  InformIT.com.


	First create a user account:  www.informit.com/join
	SAVE 40% When You Buy 2:  www.informit.com/ruby
	Add books of choice to Shopping Cart, then enter the code SAVEONRUBY during Checkout
	(Includes FREE SHIPPING within the U.S.!)

Transcript
CHUCK: So folks, this is Episode 80 -- Practical Marijuana with Steven Harms.

[laughter]



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at bluebox.net]

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to jetbrains.com/ruby]

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to rubyrogues.com/newrelic]

CHUCK: Hey everybody and welcome to Episode 80 of the Ruby Rogues Podcast! This week on our panel, we have James Edward Gray.

JOSH: Good morning everybody.

CHUCK: We also have Josh Susser.

JOSH: Hey from overcast San Francisco!

CHUCK: Avdi Grimm.

AVDI: Hello from sunny but cold, Pennsylvania!

CHUCK: I'm Charles Max Wood from devchat.tv and we have a special guest – Steven harms.

STEVEN: Hi there from… it’s actually sunny and warm, and beach house and bikinis in my district in San Francisco.

JOSH: You are in the high rank district right?

STEVEN: [chuckles] No, no I'm just two blocks away.

CHUCK: So I have to ask – I know people are going to wonder -- are you related in any way to Angela Harms?

STEVEN: No. I'm in fact no way related to any Harmses that are tech famous -- and this Steven Harms is certainly not tech famous -- so there are no famous tech Harmses that I am aware of.

JAMES: I believe Angel Harms was one of our most popular episodes ever Steve,</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:12:37</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR080PracticalMetaProgramming.mp3" fileSize="69705288" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/080-rr-practical-metaprogramming-with-steven-harms/</feedburner:origLink></item>