<item>
		<title>081 RR Rails 4 with Aaron Patterson</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RubyRogues/~3/_y-ducD_WSU/</link>
		<comments>http://rubyrogues.com/081-rr-rails-4-with-aaron-patterson/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chuck@teachmetocode.com (Charles Max Wood)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Aaron Patterson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avdi Grimm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Max Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Edward Gray II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Susser]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rubyrogues.com/?p=900</guid>
		<description>Panel Aaron Patterson (twitter github blog) Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book) James Edward Gray (blog twitter github) Josh Susser (twitter github blog) Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript) Discussion 03:06 &amp;#8211; Best of Parley Ordering of Methods by Ian M. Whitney 04:28 &amp;#8211; Everyone’s first version of Rails [...]&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RubyRogues/~4/_y-ducD_WSU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rubyrogues.com/081-rr-rails-4-with-aaron-patterson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR081Rails4.mp3" length="68221949" type="audio/mpeg"/>
		<itunes:subtitle>Panel  Aaron Patterson (twitter github blog)   Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)   James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)   Josh Susser (twitter github blog)   Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript) - </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary>Panel

	Aaron Patterson (twitter github blog)
	Avdi Grimm (twitter github blog book)
	James Edward Gray (blog twitter github)
	Josh Susser (twitter github blog)
	Charles Max Wood (twitter github Teach Me To Code Intro to CoffeeScript)

Discussion
03:06 - Best of Parley

	Ordering of Methods by Ian M. Whitney

04:28 - Everyone’s first version of Rails

06:11 - Major changes in Rails 4

	Moved tests around
	Changing directory structure

07:57 - What’s been taken out of Rails 4

	Sprockets Rails

09:31 - New deprecation policy

10:42 - Committers and the Core Team

13:07 - Release process

15:54 - Beta vs Release Candidate

17:08 - minitest vs test-unit

	minitest-spec

22:51 - routing_concerns and turbolinks

30:00 - Matryoshka Doll/Russian Doll Caching

34:20 - Rails 4 and thread safety

	WEBrick
	Heroku

39:59 - Aaron’s individual Rails 4 contributions

	Live streaming
	Bug fixes in Rails
	Refactoring in actionpack
	Ruby 2.0 Compatability

40:28 - Live streaming

41:29 - PostgresSQL

46:15 - Strong Parameters

49:14 - Queuing system

52:53 - Community participation and learning Rails
Picks

	Squeel (Avdi)
	Bulleit Bourbon (Avdi)
	The Trevor Project (Josh)
	The Pragmatic Programmer by Andrew Hunt and David Thomas (James)
	Tech Toys for Kids, From Tots to Teens (and Grown-Ups, Too) (James)
	rolify (Chuck)
	Keynote - Rails 4 and the Future of Web by Aaron Patterson (Chuck)
	ScreenFlow 4 (Aaron)
	BeagleBone(Aaron)

Next Week
Vagrant with Michael Ries
Book Club
The next Ruby Rogues Book Club Pick will be  Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby: An Agile Primer by Sandi Metz. We will be interviewing Sandi on January 2, 2013, with the episode airing January 9, 2013. The publisher, Pearson/Addison-Wesley is offering a discount via  InformIT.com.

	First create a user account:  www.informit.com/join
	SAVE 40% When You Buy 2:  www.informit.com/ruby
	Add books of choice to Shopping Cart, then enter the code SAVEONRUBY during Checkout
	(Includes FREE SHIPPING within the U.S.!)

Transcript
AARON: Avdi?

AVDI: Yes.

AARON: How come your sound is so good?

JAMES: [chuckles] It’s his voice.

JOSH: Genetics.

[laughter]

JAMES: That's awesome.



[Hosting and bandwidth provided by the Blue Box Group. Check them out at bluebox.net]

[This episode is sponsored by JetBrains, makers of RubyMine. If you like having an IDE that provides great inline debugging tools, built in version control, and intelligent code insight and refactorings, check out RubyMine by going to jetbrains.com/ruby]

[This podcast is sponsored by New Relic. To track and optimize your application performance, go to rubyrogues.com/newrelic]

CHUCK: Hey everybody and welcome to episode 81 of the Ruby Rogues podcast! This week on our panel, we have Avdi Grimm.

AVDI: Hello, hello.

CHUCK: James Edward Gray.

JAMES: So excited to be on the [inaudible] episode.

CHUCK: Josh Susser.

JOSH: No comment.

CHUCK: I'm Charles Max Wood from devchat.tv and this week, we have a special guest – Aaron Patterson.

AARON: Hi this is Avdi Grimm.

[laughter]

CHUCK: So it’s been a while since you've been in the show Aaron, do you wanna just quickly introduce yourself for the handful of folks that haven’t seen you speak at the myriad conference you’d been to?

AARON: Sure. My name is Aaron Paterson. I work on the Rails Core Team and the Ruby Core Team and I tweet as “tenderlove”. I don’t know what else to say about myself. How's that?

CHUCK: Ruby Core Team? Do you speak Japanese?

AARON: I do. Yes. It’s true.

CHUCK: [laughs]

AARON: [laughs] And I only participate in Japanese too.

CHUCK: [laughs]

AARON: …intentionally so that nobody can understand what I'm saying.

CHUCK: And by “nobody”, you mean neither the Japanese speakers nor the English speakers, right?

AARON: Exactly, yes.</itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Ruby Rogues</itunes:author>
		<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>1:11:04</itunes:duration>
	<media:content url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/rubyrogues/RR081Rails4.mp3" fileSize="68221949" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:keywords>ruby,rails,rspec,cucumber,testing,James,Edward,Gray,Charles,Max,Wood,programming,development,developer,panel,fun,funny,David,Brady</itunes:keywords><feedburner:origLink>http://rubyrogues.com/081-rr-rails-4-with-aaron-patterson/</feedburner:origLink></item>